<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</title>
        <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 17:23:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>My Path Through the World of Investing</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/my-path-investing/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 17:23:02 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/my-path-investing/</guid>
            <description>When I was 17, I was an avid fan of a Youtube channel called Teaching Men&amp;rsquo;s Fashion, or TMF. It was a style channel, with some self-improvement tips and whatnot. For a dorky teenager like I was, it was a lifesaver (although now I question a lot of my life choices regarding why I even liked that).
Even though the channel was mainly regarding fashion and grooming, in one video they talked about how one of their favorite channels was from a guy called Graham Stephan.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was 17, I was an avid fan of a Youtube channel called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Teachingmensfashion">Teaching Men&rsquo;s Fashion</a>, or TMF. It was a style channel, with some self-improvement tips and whatnot. For a dorky teenager like I was, it was a lifesaver (although now I question a lot of my life choices regarding why I even liked that).</p>
<p>Even though the channel was mainly regarding fashion and grooming, in one video they talked about how one of their favorite channels was from a guy called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/GrahamStephan">Graham Stephan</a>.</p>
<p>Graham is a real-estate agent and has a Youtube channel where he talks about all sorts of finance-related topics. And he had several videos regarding investing. That was when I found out how investing worked.</p>
<h2 id="starting-my-journey">Starting my journey</h2>
<p>The moment I started watching his videos, I was hooked. I became really interested in personal finance, budgeting, and most of all, investing your money. Graham believes that there is no good reason to not invest your money, as it is the closest thing to a bank with really high interests (if done properly).</p>
<p>He also stressed the importance of investing for your future and showed me for the first time the power of compounding and how small changes can have great impacts later on in life. And I wanted those changes.</p>
<h3 id="the-first-step">The first step</h3>
<p>After deciding I wanted in on the action, I started doing a lot of research. I wanted to invest in the stock market, have my money on index funds and do it consistently for the rest of my days.</p>
<p>So I started looking at the best online brokers available in Portugal, the ones with the lowest commissions, most markets available (I barely knew what this meant, I only wanted to have more options), and the best looking as well, which is obviously essential when choosing where to invest.</p>
<p>I settled for Degiro, which at the time seemed like the best option. I created an account, convinced my parents it would be a good idea (by this time I had turned 18, but it was good to consult them anyway), and put my money where my mouth was. The result was nothing short of a disaster.</p>
<h3 id="ambition-problems">Ambition Problems</h3>
<p>By the time I was creating the account and getting into the world of investments, I also found out about a thing called day trading. This was mainly through a channel called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/DaytradeWarrior">Warrior Trading</a>, which is not that bad and has great tips, but the problem is that it requires a totally different setup.</p>
<p>Whilst regular investing is all about slow and steady commitments and patience, day trading is fast, hectic, and requires razor-sharp attention and focus. I was hooked on the possible gains I could make, which were a lot if you did things right, which I did not, and neglected everything else. Without no experience and zero tools suitable for the job, I started day trading on Degiro.</p>
<p>What happened was that after about a week or something, I had lost nearly 20% of the money I had invested initially and was panicking at every attempt to &ldquo;trade&rdquo; I did. I was digging myself a deeper hole every time, and the only thing I wanted to do was to quit and never look at investing again.</p>
<p>On the final day that I tried this strategy, I had just lost like another 10% and was raging uncontrollably on the inside. So I just sort of went on the search, looked up two companies that I liked (Farfetch and AMD), and put all the rest of my money on them. This turned out to be one of the best decisions ever.</p>
<p>First of all, I stopped looking at the money I had or owned or whatever. I stopped worrying. I saw the numbers occasionally and didn&rsquo;t do much with them. Secondly, and best of all, those companies blew up just at the time I bought them, so I wasn&rsquo;t in a rush to sell.</p>
<p>This is what made me appreciate slow investing again, and soon enough I realized its value. I kept those stocks for around 6 months and sold them not only to cover my losses but make a huge profit along the way. This experience taught me patience. I was lucky, that&rsquo;s true, but it showed me that waiting for the market is much better than trying to predict it at any point.</p>
<h2 id="losing-track">Losing Track</h2>
<p>Although throughout this time I was still looking into investing and finance, I never actually tried to expand much besides those two stocks. University was keeping me too busy, sadly.</p>
<p>After selling those stocks, I never really got back on track and looked for other options, I collected the money and never reinvested it. Why this happened remains a mystery even for me to this day. The fact is that for the next year, I never invested again, and after that, I decided to close my account and not look back at it again.</p>
<p>It was a really bad decision. I should have kept on investing, doing it consistently, and expanding my portfolio. It would cost me nothing, and I would get the advantage of time on my side. To this day I still regret those decisions (or lack of them).</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s why I am going to change this.</p>
<h2 id="the-plan-for-the-future">The plan for the future</h2>
<p>From now on, things will be different. I cannot get my lost time back, but I can make up for it as much as I can. I have decided that I want to FatFIRE early in my life and do it with Daniela. So we will start investing as much as possible, and do it consistently like I should have done a long time ago.</p>
<p>Each of us will put money there regularly, not panic selling and overall not worrying about that money, knowing that in the future it will certainly pay off.</p>
<p>This is the plan at least. In reality, things may turn out very differently. We don&rsquo;t know. What we do know is that by not starting right now we are already missing out. So let&rsquo;s get to it.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 10</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-10/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 15:45:52 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-10/</guid>
            <description>During this week I must say that I was totally high on life.
I had a blast all week, managed to get a whole lot of work done, and even got to make an incredible trip along the way.
It was certainly exhausting, but it was one of the best weeks of this year.
But on the downside, in the middle of all this, I realized that I had forgotten something.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During this week I must say that I was totally high on life.</p>
<p>I had a blast all week, managed to get a whole lot of work done, and even got to make an incredible trip along the way.</p>
<p>It was certainly exhausting, but it was one of the best weeks of this year.</p>
<p>But on the downside, in the middle of all this, I realized that I had forgotten something. To work out!</p>
<h1 id="a-filled-week">A filled week</h1>
<p>Monday started strong from the get-go. I went to the gym as planned, had classes in the morning, and even had time to go shopping afterward. And all this in the morning. During the afternoon, I studied hard, improved on some projects, and relaxed for a bit. At night, I went out with some friends. That&rsquo;s where the problems started.</p>
<p>Although it was really fun to spend the night with them and those moments are special, when I came home it was super late and I needed to sleep. This meant that I wouldn&rsquo;t be waking up at 6 A.M to work out as usual. I slept in to not be exhausted and woke up when it was time for class.</p>
<p>Two of the seven days had passed, and I already missed one day. According to my recently signed contract, I now had to go every single other day.</p>
<h2 id="wednesday-my-beloved">Wednesday my beloved</h2>
<p>Wednesday was probably one of the best university days I had all semester, so far.</p>
<p>The first thing I did when I woke up was honor my contract and smashing my workout. I was extra motivated because I didn&rsquo;t want to lose to my contract. After that, classes went great, and I made a lot of progress on my projects. But after that came the best part. And that part was Praxe.</p>
<p>I am not going to get into too much detail about what Praxe is or my thoughts about it, because I believe that everyone should experience it for themselves and form their own opinion. I love it and think it is one of the best experiences one could get from university, but not everyone has the same opinion and it is indeed a heated topic. Maybe one day I can even write about it.</p>
<p>Either way, during this Praxe, I met up with friends from all years, we had lunch together, and after that, we got on the Subway headed to the &ldquo;Baixa&rdquo; region of Porto. Usually, the first-year students aren&rsquo;t responsible for doing things, and they only enjoy the moments we prepare for them. For this day, we made them a &ldquo;treasure hunt&rdquo; (more like geocaching) across the city.</p>
<p>First, we went to the &ldquo;Trindade&rdquo; fountain, where we hid the first of many rewards, went down the &ldquo;Aliados&rdquo; and made our way into the &ldquo;Sé&rdquo; Cathedral, the second location. We went to explore those areas, talking, having fun and everything. It was incredible.</p>
<p>Then we crossed the bridge into Gaia, relaxed for a bit, and even had time to take a few pictures. It was a really great time. Afterward, we had one more surprise for them, which was riding a boat across the Douro river!</p>
<p>We spent all afternoon together, and we were all hyped for it. In the end, we all had dinner together. Well, almost all.</p>
<p>I and some of my friends there went to another dinner that we had already agreed to go to, which made its way well into the night. When I got home it was once again way too late, which as you can probably guess meant I didn&rsquo;t wake up early enough for my workout.</p>
<h2 id="trying-to-comeback">Trying to comeback</h2>
<p>I had missed my contract because of all the partying. It was surely not motivating, and it did make me a bit sad since it meant that I went out too much. But it gave me the motivation to go all out on those other days, to try and make up for what I did.</p>
<p>Friday and Saturday I gave my all, and by the end of the week, I was just as tired as any other week. It didn&rsquo;t feel bad anymore. The contract had done its job, giving me the motivation to keep on working.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>Even though I failed what I signed on paper that I would be committed to doing, it was for sort of valid reasons, and instead, I made memories that will for sure mark my time at this university. It was the first time we had an experience like that, and it is one I will cherish for a long time. To all of those who made it possible, a big word of appreciation.</p>
<p>And now talking to me, even though you failed, you also won. You know you can&rsquo;t keep going like that, so keep trying to compromise on certain aspects and be more balanced everywhere possible. Future you will thank you. Now keep being better every day!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 9</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-9/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 08:45:54 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-9/</guid>
            <description>I have to be honest, I have been slacking off a lot on my writing.
I don&amp;rsquo;t judge myself, my schedule has been a little chaotic lately and I have been having my priorities a little mixed up, and just not enough time to sit down and do some focused thinking that wasn&amp;rsquo;t for work.
Most of my days were either spent focusing on keeping up with university work, which for a few days became pretty overwhelming, or handling other activities I do, which if they get out of control can take over all your time.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have to be honest, I have been slacking off a lot on my writing.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t judge myself, my schedule has been a little chaotic lately and I have been having my priorities a little mixed up, and just not enough time to sit down and do some focused thinking that wasn&rsquo;t for work.</p>
<p>Most of my days were either spent focusing on keeping up with university work, which for a few days became pretty overwhelming, or handling other activities I do, which if they get out of control can take over all your time. And sometimes they did.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s why I decided to take it a bit easy and start establishing priorities. I would step back a bit from those activities and try to fully enjoy them but in moderation. When I am there, I am present and enjoying as most of the moment as possible. Otherwise, I would be better off focusing on doing things for the university, going to the gym, or even writing.</p>
<h1 id="needing-to-prioritize">Needing to prioritize</h1>
<p>When talking to a few of my friends about all that I like to do, I realized that 24 hours in a day are simply not enough to do everything I want and still find time to rest properly.</p>
<p>Between working out, university, being with my girlfriend, reading, writing, and being present in Praxe (an academic tradition from Portugal), and many other things I like to do, it is simply not enough to delegate and time block, if I want to enjoy all of them fully. So instead I make compromises.</p>
<p>Every week I define what are the most important things to do. Normally, it is a combination of university, Praxe, being with my girlfriend, and working, as I consider these the biggest pillars of my life. Then, I try to make time for all other things whenever possible.</p>
<p>Usually, I try to read in the more dull moments and write on the weekends when I have more continuous free time. Also, on the weekends, I make it a priority to be with my girlfriend, to compensate for all the time I have been distant during the week.</p>
<p>The system is not ideal, but it does become effective when you commit to it, and as I use it more and more, I get better at estimating times and delegating even better.</p>
<h1 id="speaking-of-working-out">Speaking of working out</h1>
<p>But I digress, this was supposed to be a progress journal for my workouts. Contrary to what might be expected, I worked out really well this week. I remained pretty consistent, only missing Saturday because I was at my girlfriend&rsquo;s house, but made steady progress in all exercise categories.</p>
<p>Also, I became really close to hitting one of my major milestones, getting to 100 push-ups in a workout. I am already up to 90, but I believe I can progress steadily, and by next week hit my milestone.</p>
<p>Now that I am bulking up I should also try to lift a lot heavier, and maybe reduce the number of reps a bit, to try and reach overload on the weights and increase them consistently. Overall I am liking the progress a lot.</p>
<p>Also, it is pretty cool to see it in action, looking back at the weights with which I started and what I am up to now, it feels Nice. Also, I have noticed that sometimes the workouts have become a little boring as of late, maybe I should try to mix them up a bit, as I did with my core training, to make it interesting and novelty again.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>This idea to start this workout has been one of the best I ever decided to embark on. Even though it feels like it is just starting, I am almost halfway through my journey, and seeing the progress I have been doing, it seems amazing. Hopefully, when it is all over, I can start yet another workout series that will be even more demanding, and challenging, but will allow me to be much more successful.</p>
<p>I have been working out seriously for around a year and a half now, and I am really proud of what I am becoming. Keep up with this every day, and let the progress speak for itself. Let&rsquo;s get to it!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 8</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-8/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 07:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-8/</guid>
            <description>As I look back into this week, I can see that it was destined for failure from the get-go.
Although this time I had brought everything and felt prepared for the rest of the day, it quickly became quite overwhelming.
Busy scheduling Monday was still an easy day, just like every other day. I woke up early, did my full workout quite relaxed knowing I had an extra 30 minutes, and headed to class.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I look back into this week, I can see that it was destined for failure from the get-go.</p>
<p>Although this time I had brought everything and felt prepared for the rest of the day, it quickly became quite overwhelming.</p>
<h1 id="busy-scheduling">Busy scheduling</h1>
<p>Monday was still an easy day, just like every other day. I woke up early, did my full workout quite relaxed knowing I had an extra 30 minutes, and headed to class. During the afternoon, I pretty much had a free day after a small meeting and studying.</p>
<p>The problem came around every single other day, where it seemed like I couldn&rsquo;t catch a break.</p>
<p>Tuesday I had my evening busy, I still worked out but came home exhausted. Wednesday the same thing happened, and even though I had one of the best nights ever at university, it wasn&rsquo;t good for my recovery, and I ended up sleeping only around 3h that night.</p>
<p>After that, I had a day full of classes where I struggled not to fall asleep, and at night off we go to another party, sleeping not much more that night as well.</p>
<h1 id="crashing-then-burning">Crashing, then burning</h1>
<p>And you may ask. How many times did I end up working out that week? 3 times. Only 3 times.</p>
<p>That meant that only on the second week of starting my new contract I had already broken it, which was quite the bummer. Nevertheless, I paid my &ldquo;fine&rdquo;, which in this case was giving Daniela some money for her to spend, and rethought how I organize my days.</p>
<p>Also, on Tuesday, I got a real eye-opener from two friends of mine who I admire a lot. They said that even though I was there, I was not present and focused on things, not living the full experience.</p>
<p>At the time it was rough to take it, as I thought I had worked really hard to just be there and thought that everything else would follow naturally. It didn&rsquo;t. I needed to actually work on being present as well, not just hope it would happen.</p>
<p>It made me sad and I started to rethink all I had done working up to that point. Being quite a neurotic person as well, it isn&rsquo;t easy to focus for too long. But I had to try. I knew it would one day pay off.</p>
<p>The rest of the week, I tried to make things right, look up everything I had forgotten, and made an effort to commit it to memory. It is a lot harder than it seems, being on top of everything, but I wanted to prove to them and myself that I was capable of being better, both physically and mentally.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>So even though this week I had one of the best nights ever, I also got one of the most shockingly eye-opening ones, that gave me the reality check I think I needed. I hope I can prove those friends wrong in the coming future.</p>
<p>Also, as I struggled to find a way to move on, I came across a little poem that led me on the right track once again.</p>
<p>It is called Invictus, which is Latin for &ldquo;unconquerable&rdquo;, and it made me think how in life, nothing good will ever come without my work, and the power is in me to overcome everything bad the world comes at me (if you want to hear Morgan Freeman reciting it, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a7q_vACVwq0">here you go</a>). After reading and re-reading it that Tuesday night, I felt that no matter how much of life may try to put me down, I am the master of my fate, and I am the captain of my soul. Have a great week guys.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 7</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-7/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 19:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-7/</guid>
            <description>With the semester in full swing now, I can start planting the seed for a definitive routine for the rest of the year.
The plans that I had started back in Week 0 could be implemented to their fullest, and I could finally start having the real-life I wanted in university, being a T-shaped person (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of that before, here is a good article explaining it).
As usual, I came to Porto on Sunday after packing in a rush, and when I got here I didn&amp;rsquo;t even think about what I brought, I just offloaded everything and went to rest.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the semester in full swing now, I can start planting the seed for a definitive routine for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>The plans that I had started back in Week 0 could be implemented to their fullest, and I could finally start having the real-life I wanted in university, being a T-shaped person (if you haven&rsquo;t heard of that before, <a href="https://collegeinfogeek.com/become-t-shaped-person/">here</a> is a good article explaining it).</p>
<p>As usual, I came to Porto on Sunday after packing in a rush, and when I got here I didn&rsquo;t even think about what I brought, I just offloaded everything and went to rest. This proved to be a fatal mistake.</p>
<h1 id="starting-poor-then-going-hard">Starting poor, then going hard</h1>
<p>That night, as I was packing for the next day of classes, I stumbled upon some big issues. I didn&rsquo;t bring with me any towel for the gym, any water bottle, and only a single pair of gym shorts. How did this happen? I have no clue. The hurry of packing makes you forget a lot of stuff indeed.</p>
<p>This also happened by the time I signed my contract, and so could only skip at most one day of my workout per week. And I was right away forced to skip it on day 1. It made me a bit sad, not gonna lie.</p>
<p>The only upside in all that was the fact that my mom was coming to Porto that day and I asked her in time to bring everything to me.</p>
<h2 id="working-out-at-6-am">Working out at 6 A.M</h2>
<p>Every day for this week, to train well, I woke up at 6 A.M, so I could have my gym session before university started. This is a great time to train and I absolutely love it, especially knowing that everyone else is asleep and I am already ahead on the day.</p>
<p>The problem is that every night, right after dinner, I become completely exhausted and unable to do anything at all. This condition worsens on busy university days, where there are a lot of classes or things to do, and I find myself just wanting to go to bed super early, but still having to prepare everything for the next day.</p>
<p>Also, at night, I want to spend some time with Daniela, which leads to me staying up until later than I should (not her fault, I procrastinate a lot).</p>
<p>On Monday and Tuesday, this was quite tolerable, as I still was well rested from the weekend. But as the tiredness piled on, on Wednesday and especially Thursday, the lack of sleep started to show.</p>
<p>Needless to say that getting out of bed on those days was nothing short of a miracle.</p>
<h1 id="the-power-of-rest">The power of rest</h1>
<p>This week taught me a valuable lesson. Taking myself to my limit both physically and mentally is a lot more challenging than it seems at first, and without proper recovery, every day you will be more and more sluggish. Every Monday starts just fine, Tuesday as well, Tuesday night you hit start getting a bit tired, Wednesday morning is a challenge to get up, at Wednesday night you are a wreck, and Thursday morning is near impossible.</p>
<p>All of this happens because I am simply not allowing myself to recover for enough time. Given the hours on which I work out and the amount of time I am at the university studying, and other things that I have to be focused on for the whole afternoon and sometimes even at night, rest and recovery are essential.</p>
<p>This rest, at least the way I perceive it, is two-fold. First comes the actual physical rest, from all the moving around all day. The cure for that involves a lot more sitting down, and not moving as much when I am done training.</p>
<p>But the mental rest, that is the tricky part. When I spend a whole afternoon studying, I rarely think of taking breaks. When I get into a state of flow, whole hours just fly by and I don&rsquo;t even notice. It is great to be able to do this, and it is a skill that I honed over the years. But it takes its toll. And the result is a completely burnt-out Tiago by the end of Thursday.</p>
<h2 id="what-i-intend-to-do">What I intend to do</h2>
<p>From now on, I will prioritize two things. Sleep and taking breaks. Regarding sleep, I will try to sleep whenever and however much I can. For the longest of times, I thought sleeping less would be ideal, but that is clearly not the case (even though I recently discovered I can function decently on anywhere from 2:30 to 4 hours of sleep, although not for long).</p>
<p>Eight full hours per day would be ideal, but 7 of quality sleep I think would suffice. To do this, it is really simple, just go to bed earlier.</p>
<p>And while this also helps with the mental rest, the biggest gain I can think of would be to take more frequent breaks. Every 45 to 50 minutes of work, simply stopping for 10 minutes would give the rest I needed to keep going, I believe. Also, focusing less on studying a lot of time, but studying well when I decide to do so can improve my relationship with rest as well.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>Overall, while the week was certainly tiring, I feel like I gave it my all, and got out of it a much better person because of it. Maybe next week I will start getting used to this schedule and won&rsquo;t need to improve so drastically. Maybe it will get worse and I will have to take even more breaks. I won&rsquo;t know until I at least give it a try. So on we got with the plan, let&rsquo;s make this next week the best one yet!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 6</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-6/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 18:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-6/</guid>
            <description>As the start of the new semester was rapidly approaching, I decided to make sure that I would follow up and prioritize my training above almost all else (education is the major exception).
This happenned because I noticed that, during some interviews for potential internships, no one really asked me about my grades or how good my results were. People only cared about what I produced.
So, if they don&amp;rsquo;t really care about my grades, and I am learning either way, then why should I spend nearly every single minute worried about each and every little detail that won&amp;rsquo;t make a big difference in the end?</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the start of the new semester was rapidly approaching, I decided to make sure that I would follow up and prioritize my training above almost all else (education is the major exception).</p>
<p>This happenned because I noticed that, during some interviews for potential internships, no one really asked me about my grades or how good my results were. People only cared about what I produced.</p>
<p>So, if they don&rsquo;t really care about my grades, and I am learning either way, then why should I spend nearly every single minute worried about each and every little detail that won&rsquo;t make a big difference in the end?</p>
<p>Exactly, I shouldn&rsquo;t, especially not with everything else I could develop in that free time. Hence the wacky, out of nowhere decision that I hope brings good results.</p>
<p>Also, since I had just finished reading Atomic Habits, one amazing book on building good habits, I decided to cast constant votes on the fit person identity I always tries to achieve, but ended up failing to do so.</p>
<h1 id="a-contract-for-stability">A contract for stability</h1>
<p>One thing I read in the book that convinced me to take a step forward was the story of a young entrepreneur who wanted to lose weight and always failed, and decided to do what young entrepreneurs do best. He made a contract to lose weight, and made him, his wife, and his personal trainer sign it.</p>
<p>It included his goals and objectives for each quarter, and a nasty consequence if he failed. And the best part? He stuck to it. So I decided to try the same thing.</p>
<p>I got together with Daniela one weekend and decided what were the main points I was trying to develop myself in. It included the obvious like writing more and sticking to the routine, but also small things that I never got myself to do like reading more, or investing my money.</p>
<p>Also, we thought of consequences for every thing that I didn&rsquo;t do, ranging from being forced to take ice baths for a few days, to really bad things like spending a whole day without using any technology (my worst nightmare).</p>
<p>In the end I printed it out in a fancy font, asked her to sign it, and to keep me as accountable as possible during that time.</p>
<h2 id="the-power-of-accountability">The power of accountability</h2>
<p>The best part? It works! Everytime I wake up and start planning my day I immediately remind myself of the contract that is in my backpack and the consequences it presents, and I get to doing stuff right away! It is incredible how effective it is!</p>
<p>In fact, the first days I did it, in Barcelos for the last time, I didn&rsquo;t miss a single day and was on time not only for that, but for everything else I set out to do. It really felt empowering, for some strange reason. Instead of limiting me, it set me free to do the things I most wanted to do.</p>
<p>This was the last week in the &ldquo;easy&rdquo; part of the workout, and after Saturday everything would start to increase again. This meant I needed to be in top shape for all that I would do. Working out consistently really helped me achieve this goal.</p>
<h1 id="back-to-the-origins">Back to the origins</h1>
<p>On Wednesday, classes started again. And for the first time in 2 years, there wouldn&rsquo;t be a single remote class. Everything is in-person now.</p>
<p>It was great because I would see everyone again, but at the same time not, since it gives me much more constraints when it comes to my schedule. Luckily for me, I had the contract to force me to schedule things out, and boy did it work.</p>
<p>Back at the gym I would spend much more time working out, because I would have access to all the weights again and could actually do the full work, but everything was under control, because I gave it just the right amount of time for the job.</p>
<p>Also, doing the full workout is so much more fun! I am really enjoying all the new lifts and techniques I am developing, and the whole progress I am making day after day. It really puts me in a good mood for the week.</p>
<h2 id="smashing-records">Smashing records</h2>
<p>The best way to show for this work is the fact that I beat my records in all the exercises I did this week. Granted, it is still the beginning, and I am finding my actual weight limits, but for example, for the first time ever, I managed to do 90 push-ups in great form. Never in my life did I imagine I would hit such a large number!</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s these little victories that really make me feel I have made significant progress, and make me want to continue working out day after day.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up-the-week">Wrapping up the week</h1>
<p>In the end, I ended up having one of the most fullfilling weeks of workout in a long time. With the introduction of the gym, the contract and the record smashing, it is incredibly motivating to see what I can achieve with a little dedication and a sound plan.</p>
<p>It is still in the beginning, but I am already feeling it&rsquo;s gonna have a tremendous impact on my life. Let&rsquo;s hope I can keep this momentum going to the next week. Let&rsquo;s get to it!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 5</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 16:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-5/</guid>
            <description>This was most definitely a week of adaptation. After the first week of vacations had passed, I went back to my hometown to be with my parents for a while. This led to some great times of course, but also some workout difficulties.
Choosing a new spot In previous times, I would be fine working out in Barcelos, as I had a gym close to home during summer break. The problem is that I only could go to that gym for summer break.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was most definitely a week of adaptation. After the first week of vacations had passed, I went back to my hometown to be with my parents for a while. This led to some great times of course, but also some workout difficulties.</p>
<h1 id="choosing-a-new-spot">Choosing a new spot</h1>
<p>In previous times, I would be fine working out in Barcelos, as I had a gym close to home during summer break. The problem is that I only could go to that gym for summer break. It didn&rsquo;t make sense for me to buy a subscription and then cancel it after only a week, paying a lot of extra money along the way.</p>
<p>That meant that for week 5, I wouldn&rsquo;t have access to a gym, so most of the workout was nullified. While a bit demotivating, I didn&rsquo;t want to give up on training completely for the week. So I tried to find the one thing that I thought I needed most to at least make some progress. And that is the humble bar.</p>
<h2 id="the-search-begins">The search begins</h2>
<p>The humble pull-up bar is the only real equipment I need to have a decent workout. &ldquo;Why?&rdquo;, you ask? Well, there are great calisthenic exercises that can train the &ldquo;push&rdquo; muscles, like the chest, shoulders, and triceps.</p>
<p>But sadly, for the back and biceps, you can&rsquo;t really train them without &ldquo;pulling&rdquo; anything, and the easiest thing to pull is, well, your body. But for that, you need somewhere to pull your body from. Enter the bar. The pull-up and its variations are probably some of the best exercises for your back and biceps, and I wanted to keep them in decent shape.</p>
<p>So I set out to find a decent pull-up bar from walking distance of my home, so I could train there. I settled for quite an unusual place. A children&rsquo;s swing.</p>
<p>It was in a little public park close to home that was built recently, and during the day no one is there usually, so it was nearly the ideal spot (that park could have had a pull-up bar but the people in charge decided it was not a good idea, something I think is quite dumb but oh well).</p>
<p>Here is where I did most of my training, which focused on the calisthenics side of the workout.</p>
<p>Luckily for me though, I managed to find some small weights lying around at home, so not all was lost when it came to gym training. Granted, it wasn&rsquo;t ideal at all, especially for chest where I need much larger weights, but for the shoulders and triceps, they did the job.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>Overall it was a week of small changes, some adaptations, and a bit of relaxation in between. It wasn&rsquo;t great for development (even though now I am at max reps for all calisthenic exercises, ready to upgrade), but I needed some of the rest to recover from a strenuous semester at university. Now I am fully charged and ready to go off for the next 4 months, and I feel great. So let&rsquo;s get to it!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 4</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 13:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-4/</guid>
            <description>After such an intensive week like week 3, week 4 started out in a really slow fashion.
It was impressive how little physical stamina I had up to this point, and Friday and the futsal game really showed it. The coming days were challenging as hell, with Saturday and Sunday me being barely able to move my muscles and lift my legs, which led to me not leaving the house at all.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After such an intensive week like week 3, week 4 started out in a really slow fashion.</p>
<p>It was impressive how little physical stamina I had up to this point, and Friday and the futsal game really showed it. The coming days were challenging as hell, with Saturday and Sunday me being barely able to move my muscles and lift my legs, which led to me not leaving the house at all.</p>
<p>Saturday I would be crazy to try to train, since it was leg day worst of all, and after my rest day I still wasn&rsquo;t feeling up to it, so Monday I decided to not go for it either. I had to break the chain that I was building so well up to that point, but I really needed the rest or I would start to get real problems.</p>
<p>After Monday though, I started feeling fine again, and so Tuesday I went onward with my progress</p>
<h2 id="tuesday---shaking-things-up">Tuesday - Shaking things up</h2>
<p>As I came to workout on Tuesday, I had also scheduled a physical evaluation that the gym offers, just to see how I was doing.</p>
<p>It was a bit sad to realize that during this time, I had actually gained fat and not that much muscle, so the workouts weren&rsquo;t adding up to much. Something had to change. Luckily for me, the coach that gave me the evaluation also provided me with a full workout regimen to improve my strength.</p>
<p>I took the advice he gave very seriously, and after talking with him to see my goals, the workout I got was the perfect complement to this &ldquo;challenge&rdquo;. It trains every part of my body completely, and includes some of the heavy compound lifts I always wanted to try, like military press, deadlift, squat and bench press.</p>
<p>All in all, I now had a comprehensive gym strength training, coupled with a solid core and calisthenics workout as well as a cardio routine. I had everything. The only thing that I need is to actually follow it.</p>
<h2 id="wednesday---a-first-try-out">Wednesday - A first try out</h2>
<p>The first day I used this full workout regimen was Wednesday and it was a blast. I started slow on some of the exercises, but always tried to reach failure in all of them. The end result is me being a complete wreck, but feeling as powerful as possible.</p>
<p>Also, during this time I was on vacation from school, so I really could afford to spend time perfecting my form.</p>
<h2 id="thursday---one-small-day-off">Thursday - One small day off</h2>
<p>Up until this week I was in a complete frenzy to finish my exams and try to get the best grades possible in all of them. My girlfriend was doing the exact same thing. The problem with this is that we ended up studying and cramming on Valentine&rsquo;s Day, and barely had time for ourselves. What is the good part in the middle of this, you ask?</p>
<p>Well, Thursday we were both completely free, and since it was no longer Valentine&rsquo;s Day, we could have our very own special day without the huge crowds of people doing the same thing. And we did.</p>
<p>In the morning we went to explore around the Porto riverside, relaxed, and crossed the bridge over to Gaia. Here we had sushi for lunch, in a restaurant that on Valentine&rsquo;s was completely packed, but on this day was nearly empty, so we could have quality time to ourselves. After this we went to &ldquo;Jardim do Morro&rdquo; to appreciate the views, hopped on a bus and went over to the &ldquo;Foz&rdquo; area to play mini-golf!</p>
<p>It was a wonderful evening, and a good break from all the hustle and bustle of university.</p>
<h2 id="friday---making-up-for-lost-time">Friday - Making up for lost time</h2>
<p>As Thursday I took a day off, Friday I made up for it, big time. I went to the gym a bit early, because we had our train in the afternoon, and tried to get myself as tired as possible in the short time I had. I quite easily succeeded in this endeavor, and came home exhausted, to pack and head home to Barcelos.</p>
<p>It was a kind of boring gym day, but I was starting to see some progress after a month of trying.</p>
<h2 id="rounding-out-the-week">Rounding out the week</h2>
<p>The final days of the week I failed for a bit. On Saturday it was because I wasn&rsquo;t yet done adapting the routine to my new place for the week, where I wouldn&rsquo;t have a gym, but on Sunday I made up for it and did the workout I was meant to do Saturday.</p>
<p>All in all, this week was the start of a period of change. With the new workout coupling perfectly with the existing routine, some slight tweaks to my times and a newfound will, I now have every tool to have an impressive journey forward. Let&rsquo;s go out and get it!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>2 Years Since the Best Trip of My Life</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/trip-to-london/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 21:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/trip-to-london/</guid>
            <description>This is the story of the best gift I ever received, and one of the best I probably will ever receive.
The Origin Story It all started when I turned 18. It is always a special occasion, and with me being born late in December, it was even more exciting after seeing all of my friends having their great parties and moments.
That year was also the year I started dating Daniela, so it was even better as it was my first birthday I would spend with a &amp;ldquo;special someone&amp;rdquo;, something every teen would love to have.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[
    <img src="/trip-to-london/cover.png"  alt="Me and Daniela having the best time of our lives"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>This is the story of the best gift I ever received, and one of the best I probably will ever receive.</p>
<h2 id="the-origin-story">The Origin Story</h2>
<p>It all started when I turned 18. It is always a special occasion, and with me being born late in December, it was even more exciting after seeing all of my friends having their great parties and moments.</p>
<p>That year was also the year I started dating Daniela, so it was even better as it was my first birthday I would spend with a &ldquo;special someone&rdquo;, something every teen would love to have.</p>
<p>But the best thing to come out of that day was not the party, it was not the amazing food that my parents made, it was much greater than that. It was cleanup time after all the guests were gone, and in a quite unusual fashion, my father called me to talk. I arrived in the kitchen and both of my parents said, much like the Apple keynotes, that &ldquo;there is one more thing&rdquo;.</p>
<p>At that moment they reveal that I have one more gift, from them, and that it was the chance to go to London for half a week, with 1 other person that I would wish to come with me. I didn&rsquo;t even know what to say. I was shocked at what was offered and didn&rsquo;t understand what they told me (at first I even thought they were joking), but it was real, I could go to London, one of my favorite places in the world, with whoever I wanted. This was incredible.</p>
<p>Obviously, I told them yes, and right after that, I asked them if it was ok if I took Daniela with me, to which they said they were already expecting that answer and were more than fine with me going with her. This was one of the best feelings possible. Knowing that I can travel to one of the best cities in the world with my girlfriend was such an amazing thing. I immediately told her, and as soon as she got confirmation from her parents a few days after, we started planning.</p>
<h2 id="setting-the-plan">Setting the Plan</h2>
<p>Since we were going for essentially 3 days, we wanted to see as much as possible in the short time we had there. That meant we needed a solid itinerary that would take us to the most important things, seeing what we both wanted and wasting as little time as possible in transportation, while still feeling like a relaxed yet fast-paced journey. Also, since it was quite an expensive gift, and I didn&rsquo;t want to spend any more money, we also took into account the prices of things and chose the cheapest options for everything, which is quite fun.</p>
<p>All the planning got both of us even more hyped to go, and looking at the different ways we could visit and go to places made us find even more special things and places to add to the trip.</p>
<p>With countless nights seeing the possible visiting destinations, estimating prices, and finding the fastest routes that didn&rsquo;t break the bank, we finally had a detailed plan on how to have the most amazing journey possible. In the end, it looked something like this:</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/plan.jpeg"  alt="A snippet of the final plan for visiting London"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<h2 id="day-1-the-arrival">Day 1: The Arrival</h2>
<p>Our flight was at around 6 A.M, which means that at around 3:30 I was already awake and getting ready to leave. That night I barely slept, and not for lack of trying. Daniela tried and did sleep. She is lucky in that aspect. But neither of us cared even if we didn&rsquo;t sleep at all. We were so excited it kept us wide awake. We arrived at the airport, all still pitch black outside, I gave the goodbyes to my parents and so we went to board. I never had gone to an airport alone like that. All of a sudden it felt like I was an adult, with responsibilities. It&rsquo;s scary, but the freedom you get at the same time is incredible. I was kind of in shock all that time, like it didn&rsquo;t feel real. But it was. I really was going to London with my girlfriend.</p>
<p>Check-in was complete, shops visited, and all of a sudden we were boarding the plane. At that moment I found out my godfather (who is my cousin) and his wife were going on the same journey as us. It was fun hanging out with them, and knowing that after all, I wasn&rsquo;t completely alone in London, in case something happened.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/departure.jpg"  alt="Me boarding the plane"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>This is me boarding the plane, still a bit flabbergasted about going.</p>
<p>The flight took off, and the journey was well underway. The time in the air is really good to calm down and let the body relax. So we did. We talked, played games, and tried to prepare for what was coming. But nothing could prepare us for how amazing everything would get in a bit.</p>
<p>We arrived at 9 A.M and were instantly met by the freezing cold of being so far up north. It was freezing the entire journey. But it felt good. We walked around in heavy jackets all the time and not for one moment were we cold or sweating, something that happens after 20 minutes in Portugal. It was amazing. And so the journey began. We went through the massive building that is the Stansted airport, figured out where the train was, and off we were into the heart of London, Liverpool Street Station.</p>
<p>When we got there, we knew exactly what to do. We had planned all this. It felt so good to have that plan, so we didn&rsquo;t feel overwhelmed at all. But still, we were. We had made it to one of the coolest cities in the world!</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/subway.jpg"  alt="The London subway in all its glory"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>We got off at our first stop, Queensway, and went straight to the hotel we were going to stay. It was small but cozy. For the time we would spend there, it was more than enough.</p>
<p>Check-in was done, and we suddenly realized something. We hadn&rsquo;t eaten since like 4 A.M and it was already midday. So we found a cheap place to eat, and we weren&rsquo;t disappointed.</p>
<p>Now, the exploring began. Since we were going to be quite sleep-deprived, there were 3 main places to visit on day 1:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hyde Park</li>
<li>The Natural History Museum</li>
<li>Harrods department store</li>
</ul>
<p>Right after we had eaten, we went to a little store to buy some supplies a.k.a food and water for whenever we got hungry while traveling.</p>
<h4 id="hyde-park">Hyde Park</h4>
<p>Our first real sight was London&rsquo;s biggest park, Hyde Park. It always seemed huge on the map, but only when we entered it to cross did we realize just how huge it is. It seemed to stretch forever, and it was full of trees, lakes, animals, everything. It seemed like a really happy place, and we loved to go to the lake where there were a ton of swans, ducks, and whatnot, just because we had never seen anything as big as that. We stopped to admire the magnitude of it all, the animals all around the lake, and we went on with our journey.</p>
<p>Just to go across the park it seemed like a massive walk, and we went through the short side!</p>
<p>Also at this point, we were starting to realize something. We would be walking a lot. Like 20km a day a lot. None of us had the kind of feet for that. This was getting evident when, just as we were getting out of Hyde Park, my feet started getting a little sore. This would become a recurring event in the coming days. But at that point, it was quite manageable, and wasn&rsquo;t all that bad, for the moment.</p>
<p>So out we went, and the first of the many amazing places was officially checked off the list.</p>
<h4 id="natural-history-museum">Natural History Museum</h4>
<p>The next stop was the magic Natural History Museum.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/nat-hist-entrance.jpg"  alt="The entrance to the Natural History Museum"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>I had seen pictures of this place before. But nothing could prepare me for what was in front of me at this moment. It was so big!</p>
<p>I always loved these sorts of museums, but none of the ones I had seen looked as giant as this one. Just entering and being immediately greeted by the huge whale skeleton is breathtaking, and sets you up for a whole afternoon of entertainment.</p>
<p>Right after you walk through this massive entrance, you are greeted with this:</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/whale.jpg"  alt="The giant whale skeleton at the entrance"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>Behind it sits a statue of the great Charles Darwin, a great symbol for all that was found inside this museum.</p>
<p>Inside the massive corridors sit a million different exhibits showcasing everything from dinosaur fossils and models, all the animal kingdoms showed in all their glory, the life of the giant sequoia trees to the history of the earth itself. Anything that was an important part of the Earth, you can find a piece of it here.</p>
<p>Needless to say, me and Daniela were starstruck. Me especially, having spent a lot of my childhood seeing things like these on TV, finally seeing them in real life was an experience I can never forget. We spent around 3 hours here, and it all seemed to just fly by.</p>
<p>The only thing that grounded us a bit and started to take its toll was our feet. Inside the museum, we walked through every single surface possible and it showed. We must have done a few kilometers in there, not stopping for a bit. In the end, they were really hurting and the lack of sleep started to show a lot. We were getting exhausted. But we pushed on, as we had just one more thing to see&hellip;</p>
<h4 id="harrods">Harrods</h4>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/harrods-entry.jpg"  alt="The entry to Harrods"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>By this point, we were a total wreck.</p>
<p>After walking quite a bit to get here, our feet were completely dead, the sleep was making us slow, and also, we developed a bit of hunger. Needless to say, it was not as fun to visit as we had hoped. At least it was the thing we least felt the need to visit in the whole trip, so not taking it in fully wasn&rsquo;t the end of the world. We would&rsquo;ve been much sadder if this happened in the Natural History Museum.</p>
<p>One thing that was quite a sight to see was the architecture of the buildings around it. Everything seemed just so fancy and expensive like it was made for royalty. Just after going there, I found out we were just a few meters away from some of the most expensive apartments in the whole world, so it was clear that we were in the middle of real money.</p>
<p>In the store, there were booths for Gucci, Prada, Fendi, Versace, and all that you can imagine. For us, it was something we had never seen. The butcher and pastries sections were also beautiful, like everything inside it. But we made our visit fast, so our feet would stop hurting so much.</p>
<h4 id="winding-down-for-the-day">Winding down for the day</h4>
<p>After we went out, we stopped at a nearby Starbucks just to rest the feet and stop for a bit, after hours and hours of non-stop walking and standing up. It felt nice to just relax for a few minutes. We figured out where to have dinner, and chose to try out the infamous &ldquo;cheeky Nando&rsquo;s&rdquo;.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/nandos.jpg"  alt="Our dinner at Nandos"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>It was definitely not bad, but coming from the country where that food is super popular (the logo even is the symbol of our hometown, the &ldquo;Galo de Barcelos&rdquo;), it could have been a bit better. But still, it was quite the treat after all that walking.</p>
<p>After this, we were completely exhausted as we got to the hotel. We arrived, showered, got into bed, and almost passed out immediately. It was an amazing day. But we had to rest as the next one would be even bigger.</p>
<h2 id="day-2-exploring-around-london">Day 2: Exploring around London</h2>
<p>The second day was going to be the biggest one. It was the first full day we would have to explore and so we needed to take advantage of it. The plan had us traveling north, starting from the Thames and ending in the big center of London, Picadilly Circus.</p>
<p>Through it we would pass by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Buckingham Palace</li>
<li>Westminster Abbey</li>
<li>The Houses of Parliament</li>
<li>Big Ben</li>
<li>Chinatown</li>
<li>The British Museum</li>
<li>Oxford Street</li>
<li>Picadilly Circus</li>
</ul>
<p>And more. Yeah, it was packed.</p>
<p>We woke up early in the morning, after a not-so-good night&rsquo;s sleep because of all the heat that was blasting from the radiator we didn&rsquo;t know how to control, and the freezing cold of the window we opened to fight it. We had our breakfast, eating a lot to have energy for the day, and try to cure the lingering pain in our feet, and off we went.</p>
<p>First stop, the Royal House.</p>
<h4 id="buckingham-palace">Buckingham Palace</h4>
<p>We got off the subway and we knew right away we were in the right place. The massive royal building, the beautiful black and gold gates, the red guards everywhere, it was quite the sight to see.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/buckingham.jpg"  alt="A shot of Buckingham Palace"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px; margin-bottom: 10px"  />



    <img src="/trip-to-london/gates.jpg"  alt="A side gate to one of the gardens"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>The best part was the fact that right after we got there, the sun started shining and illuminating everything making the buildings seem even more powerful.</p>
<p>Everything around that area seemed superbly clean and organized, and since it was mostly empty (at least compared to a lot of the places we had been through so far), we could have more liberty to explore. Just imagining that inside those walls lives an actual Queen, and we were so close to actual royalty is really cool.</p>
<p>We wanted to stay for the change of guard with all the ceremony, but we had to move on with the plan. Not without snapping a few pics before going though. Just look at this one, Daniela looks amazing!</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/daniela-buckingham.jpg"  alt="A picture of Daniela next to Buckingham Palace"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>Next stop, the riverside!</p>
<h4 id="westminster-abbey">Westminster Abbey</h4>
<p>Funny story, I am really bad at figuring out which important building is which. When in a city where every building seems important like in London, this condition worsens, tremendously. This effect was shown quite well when we were walking to try and find Westminster Abbey, walking just by it, totally ignoring it thinking it is just any other church, looking for &ldquo;the real Westminster Abbey&rdquo;, wasting nearly half an hour or more until I figured out we had just passed by it.</p>
<p>At one point, I was convinced that the houses of Parliament were what we were looking for. That lasted until the absurd amount of police guarding the entrance made me think that maybe that wasn&rsquo;t it.</p>
<p>When Daniela made me realize it, she first mocked me and kept doing so for the next days, and then we got into the Abbey.</p>
<p>Seeing the resting place of legends I have always admired like Sir Isaac Newton, Stephen Hawking, Charles Darwin, it felt like standing on the shoulders of giants. The Scientist&rsquo;s Corner was the part I most admired, but seeing names like Charles Dickens in there, or the Tomb of the Unknown Warrior, which was kept pristine at all times, made us realize we were in the middle of greatness.</p>
<p>We couldn&rsquo;t take any pictures while inside, but those halls, we will never forget.</p>
<h4 id="houses-of-parliament-and-the-big-ben">Houses of Parliament and the Big Ben</h4>
<p>Down we went closer to the Thames, where we saw the world-famous London Eye and had to control ourselves deeply to not go on a ride (the queue was massive and we wouldn&rsquo;t have time for anything else). So we just lounged around the area of the mighty Big Ben and the Houses of Parliament, we took a few more pictures of the amazing buildings, and then we went with our way.</p>
<p>Here the most surprising thing that happened was when we went to a Tesco to fill up on snacks for the day, and it was just so tiny! The whole shop was barely the size of a corridor, and two people could not fit inside when looking for things. I had never seen anything like it before, we were both quite shocked. But we had our food, so everything was ok.</p>
<h4 id="trafalgar-square">Trafalgar Square</h4>
<p>After this, our path up through London began, and the first stop was the gigantic Trafalgar Square. It was full of life, with people traveling everywhere and many of them visiting the famous National Gallery, which we sadly didn&rsquo;t go to. But once again the sun was shining, so we took some more pictures, and this time I am the one that looks quite nice, just look:</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/tiago-trafalgar.jpg"  alt="A picture of me next to the National Gallery"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>It was a cool place to be. But by this time, we had developed quite an appetite. So off we went to search for our lunch. The first thing we encountered was Chinatown, vibrant as ever and it looked like a super cool place to have lunch. Sadly, Daniela didn&rsquo;t find any of them appetizing enough, so I had another idea, to try out the classic British delicacy that is fish and chips!</p>
<p>Sadly, it was one of the big letdowns of the journey. For the time we waited and the price we paid, it is clear that it was a tourist trap above all else. But at least I can&rsquo;t say I didn&rsquo;t try it, however disappointing it may have been. It was also the first time any of us had fresh cod since in Portugal almost all of it is salted to be preserved. I hate salted cod, but the fresh one was really good for a change. We should invest in it more.</p>
<h4 id="british-museum">British Museum</h4>
<p>After relaxing a bit in the restaurant and letting our feet heal for a moment, we went to our last big destination for the day, the mighty British Museum. As we got there, there we started to realize its magnitude, but boy, were we in for a treat.</p>
<p>The entrance alone is one of the most beautiful museum entrances I have seen (even after entering the Natural History one), and the architecture inside is so beautiful.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/british-entrance.jpg"  alt="The ceiling on the entrance of the British Museum"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>You are met with this huge glass ceiling that sits above the entire room, creating a mood lighting like no other. On each of the other 3 sides, there is a massive hallway that will take you through a journey through different periods of history. Unlike the Natural History Museum, this one is focused on humans, and our history throughout the world. From the Greeks and Romans, the ancient oriental world, the mighty land of Egypt and its famous Rosetta Stone, everything about human history and more could be found in these walls.</p>
<p>Each corner of the museum left me more amazed than the previous, with rooms for absolutely everything. It was fascinating seeing some of the pieces they have collected over the years, and the history each one tells. It was yet another experience I will never forget. But, being honest, if I had to choose between this and the Natural History Museum, I would favor the latter (I love animals, sue me). Daniela prefers this one, and that is why we visited both.</p>
<p>After around 4 hours of non-stop exploring this place, we were decimated by our feet. We stopped on some stairs by the bar and chilled around for some time, as on the second day our feet were really, really hurt. Daniela suffered even more, as her shoes provided little support, so she definitely needed that rest.</p>
<p>After both of us felt better, it was already dark outside, so it was time for some big treats.</p>
<h4 id="picadilly-circus">Picadilly Circus</h4>
<p>When we got out it was super dark, which was the perfect setting for our final destinations. First stop, getting the now world-famous Bubblewrap. We had seen it on a Youtube video, and since we were close we decided to give it a try. The result speaks for itself:</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/bubblewrap.jpg"  alt="A bubblewrap waffle in Chinatown"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>It was delicious, and even made us forget how much our feet were sore!</p>
<p>After walking a bit down the streets of London, and seeing things we never heard of like a Harry Potter theater, we arrived at the hustle and bustle that is Picadilly Circus.</p>
<p>It was the brightest place I had ever seen at night. The giant screens made it feel like daytime, and the number of people walking around told us this was the place to be at night in London.</p>
<p>There was music, street performers, tourists, and locals everywhere, hanging around this area. It felt like we were a part of the nightlife of London, and we kind of were!</p>
<p>With all the admiration still hitting us, we looked closely and found one of the happiest places on Earth. An M&amp;M store! Obviously, we had to visit it, not only to see for ourselves but also to get a lot of free candy.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/candy-shop.jpg"  alt="Some of the dispensers in the candy store"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>We came out very very happy, but even more so when we found out the fun wasn&rsquo;t over, because just across the street in Leicester Square there was a huge Lego store!</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/lego.jpg"  alt="A Lego Replica of the Subway train"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>We both are huge fans of Legos, and seeing what they built here made us feel like children again. Needless to say, this was one of the best nights of my life.</p>
<p>After it started getting late, and our feet just couldn&rsquo;t take it anymore, we went back to the hotel, already limping and crawling at this point (or so it seemed), we lied in bed, and once again we completely passed out from how tired we were.</p>
<p>This was one of the best days of my life, and the memories I still hold of it show this clearly.</p>
<h2 id="day-3-soaring-up-the-sky">Day 3: Soaring up the sky</h2>
<p>For our final day of exploring, we chose to visit the more historic and ancient side of London, the &ldquo;City of London&rdquo; (yes, London has a City of London inside it, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/City_of_London">check it out</a>). This is where the history of London begins and was also the furthest part from where we were staying, so we decided to dedicate a whole day to it. Also, we made heavy use of the <a href="https://londonpass.com/en-us">London Pass</a>, so we could visit as many places as we could and save money along the way</p>
<p>The main parts of our visit for this day included:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Tower of London</li>
<li>St. Paul&rsquo;s Cathedral</li>
<li>The Tower Bridge</li>
<li>The Shard</li>
</ul>
<p>So, early in the morning, we woke up, once again tired because of the non-stop walking and not-so-good sleep of the night before, and out we went on to the subway, to the furthest ride we took so far.</p>
<p>When we got off, we knew right away that the area was meant for business. Massive office buildings soaring up the sky, some with incredible modern architecture like the sky garden building and the gherkin, being also some of the tallest buildings we had ever seen, and the classic ones like the Bank of England, which we passed right by and didn&rsquo;t even realize at the time.</p>
<p>Also, another incredible (and a bit eerie) sight to see was just how empty the streets were. Since it was an office area and everyone was working, we barely saw anyone until we got very close to the Tower of London, which is really weird in one of the biggest cities in the world, surrounded by those massive buildings. It felt as if we went somewhere we weren&rsquo;t supposed to. But on we went anyway, and soon enough we reached our first destination for the day.</p>
<h4 id="tower-of-london">Tower of London</h4>
<p>Our knowledge of the tower of London beforehand was essentially none, so when we went inside we were amazed by the history that was made there, and the significance it had for building a city like London. Inside the walls, we were surprised to see that there seemed to be a small city, with housing and everything inside it. It turns out that the guards live there, and they have their houses and families inside those walls!</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/tower-bridge.jpg"  alt="Me with the Tower Bridge as background"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>Our visit was going to be huge since inside the walls there are a ton of things to explore. We saw how the tower came to be, the walls that guarded it (took a few obligatory pictures overlooking the Tower Bridge), saw how the people inside the walls lived, how the tower was used as a prison at one point, and even some of the markings left by people incarcerated in it. When the walls were explored we moved to see maybe the biggest treasure held inside, the Crown Jewels.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/jewels-building.jpg"  alt="The building where the Crown Jewels are stored"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>Inside this build were some of the most beautiful objects we had ever seen. The presentation, the significance, the radiance they gave out, they almost didn&rsquo;t feel real. We also saw the chair where Queen Elizabeth was coronated, and the people who guarded it gave us a small talk on how everything worked. It was incredible.</p>
<p>After visiting the outer buildings and walls, we moved on to the centerpiece, the tower that gave the place its name. Here we saw the battle armor of some warriors (and kings), the biggest and smallest armors in the world, some of the weapons used to fight in the older days, and even a totally accurate interpretation of a Middle-Ages armored dragon! (They were totally real and if you think otherwise we are no longer friends).</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/dragon.jpg"  alt="A dragon made out of armor pieces"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>This was a place riddled with history, and we could have spent the whole day there.</p>
<p>And finally, when all the buildings were visited, there was one more thing left to stun us. The wildlife! This was the first time either of us had seen actual squirrels in person! They are some of the cutest animals that exist and they roamed freely inside the walls, climbing trees and running around.</p>
<p>It was so cute seeing them in person for the first time. We couldn&rsquo;t help but try to capture this moment.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/squirrel.jpg"  alt="A squirrel digging a hole"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>After all the buildings were visited, the feet were dying and the morning was spent in absolute delight, we headed off for lunch. Who would&rsquo;ve guessed that walking for 4 hours worked quite the appetite?</p>
<p>We decided to try a burger chain that I had heard of from the U.S but sadly doesn&rsquo;t exist in Portugal, Five Guys. And boy was that a good choice.</p>
<p>It was one of the best burgers I ever had in my life. The condiments, the meat, the massive lot of fries that came with it, the unlimited drinks. I had never seen anything like it. But we were most certainly in burger heaven. We stayed there for a bit as our feet were recovering, had some of the complimentary peanuts while talking, and when we were feeling better, moved on to the next big attraction of the day.</p>
<h4 id="st-pauls-cathedral">St. Paul&rsquo;s Cathedral</h4>
<p>Luckily for us, we didn&rsquo;t have to walk much to get here. The restaurant was just across the street.</p>
<p>When we walked in, it felt a lot like we got to a different city. The massive dome, the Renaissance style of architecture, it seemed as we had teleported right into the middle of Italy. This church was one of the most stand-out buildings for me. Maybe it was the massive architecture, the arches inside, the paintings and details, but it felt much more like a special place than say, Westminster Abbey. It was simply massive. And the decoration was impressive. Just look at this ceiling, for example.</p>
<p>
    <img src="/trip-to-london/stpauls-ceiling.png"  alt="The ceiling on St.Paul&#39;s Cathedral"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px; margin-bottom: 10px"  />



    <img src="/trip-to-london/stpauls-ceiling-detail.jpg"  alt="The details of the ceiling on St.Paul&#39;s Cathedral"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px; margin-bottom: 10px"  />



    <img src="/trip-to-london/stpauls-dome.jpg"  alt="The dome on St.Paul&#39;s Cathedral"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px; margin-bottom: 10px"  />



    <img src="/trip-to-london/stpauls-decor.jpg"  alt="The decoration around the walls on St.Paul&#39;s Cathedral"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

</p>
<p>It was magical being here, and simply admiring the architecture of the place. And what was the best part of this? It was just one of the 3 levels we could visit! Turns out we could (and did) go to the basement and the roof!</p>
<p>In the basement were buried some of the biggest names in the history of Britain, like the Duke of Wellington and others alike. It was a place for more respect, and we simply admired how those great men were left resting.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the final (and possibly best) part of our visit was going to be visiting the roof. We had to walk up the dome to do so, which was quite the experience (it took a solid 10 minutes of going up the stairs, and walking through some very narrow corridors, through which I could barely pass with two backpacks), but finally, we had made it. And boy did it pay off. The view was one of the best I had ever seen. We felt at the top of the world. We could overlook the entirety of London. These were some of the best moments of my life.</p>
<p>
    <img src="/trip-to-london/financial-skyline.jpg"  alt="The view of the financial district on St.Paul&#39;s Cathedral"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px; margin-bottom: 10px"  />



    <img src="/trip-to-london/alloflondon.jpg"  alt="A wide view of London"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px; margin-bottom: 10px"  />



    <img src="/trip-to-london/church-view.jpg"  alt="The view of the side of St.Paul&#39;s Cathedral"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px; margin-bottom: 10px"  />



    <img src="/trip-to-london/ground-view.jpg"  alt="Another skyline viewed from St.Paul&#39;s Cathedral"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

</p>
<p>We were in the clouds, figuratively and literally. We wanted to stay there forever. But sadly, we had to go. It was also at this moment that I realized that our incredible trip was nearing its end. We had just one more planned item and that was it. Sadly, the moments that made us cross the sky also brought us down to earth quickly.</p>
<p>But that sadness quickly faded when I looked back and saw what an amazing journey we were having, and how happy Daniela was to be in a place like that. I shouldn&rsquo;t be sad because it was ending, I should be happy with all we made in those 3 very short days.</p>
<p>And so I quickly picked myself up, and on we went to our final destination, where we would take one step further in the climb up, to the tallest building in all the United Kingdom, the Shard.</p>
<h4 id="the-shard">The Shard</h4>
<p>As we were walking towards it the sun was starting to set, and a lovely mood started to set in the city. The lights dimmed, but a beautiful shade of blue persisted in the air. I had never seen evenings like it before. Throughout the day we could see the building in the distance, as it is simply massive, but as we headed closer and closer we started to really take a grasp of the dimensions of the place.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/shard-sunset.jpg"  alt="A view of the Shard at sunset"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>At one point, it seemed to reach up to the sky, and as the sky became darker, the yellow top looked like a torch lighting up the night. Those were sights we would never forget.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/shard-night.jpg"  alt="The Shard at night"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>We stopped at a nearby Costa Coffee to freshen up a bit (and also stop walking for a few moments to recharge), and on we walked through the mighty Tower Bridge, just as the night came down. It was packed with people, all walking along to admire its beauty. And it sure was quite a sight. But it wasn&rsquo;t our main stopping point.</p>
<p>We walked through it and admired it of course, but didn&rsquo;t pay that much attention, as all the environment was soaking us in, including the massive building that we were getting nearer and nearer.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/bridge.jpg"  alt="Walking through the Tower Bridge"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>When we got on the other side, we really started realizing the true size of this piece of architecture. It seemed to rip through the sky and never end. And we were headed straight to the top!</p>
<p>Up until this point, the tallest building I ever recall being on had like 10 floors and was a department store (it was also the first time I saw double digits on floors). Never did I expect to be entering a building that had not 10, not 20, but 72 floors, and I was going to be in the very top one!</p>
<p>Also, the tallest building in the entirety of Portugal is the Vasco da Gama Tower, standing at 145m tall. This was more than double. At almost 310 meters, I had never felt so much in the sky.</p>
<p>We found the entrance, waited along the queue, and as we reached the elevator, I started to think that it would take an eternity for them to reach 72 floors. I couldn&rsquo;t be more wrong. First of all, we had to take 2 elevators, one up to the 40th something floor and another to the top. And second of all, these were some really fast elevators. Like really fast. Like &ldquo;pressure in your ears from the speed&rdquo; fast.</p>
<p>The floor numbers were moving so fast on the screen inside we thought they were fake. But just as quickly as we entered the first one, we reached the top. I once lived on the 4th floor of an apartment whose elevator was slower than that. So it was quite impressive seeing something like that happen.</p>
<p>I am not the person to be scared of heights, it had never happened to me. But boy, when those doors opened, we climbed the set of stairs and were met with the open top of that massive building, something inside sure started to scream. It was so weird being that far up, seeing everything down below like tiny specs in a massive painting. The last floor comprised of a bar, a lounge area, and the windows, which everyone stuck to.</p>
<p>The little time we spent close to one was one of the most magical we ever had. Seeing it all from above, soaring up the sky, looking at everything we had visited in these last few days, the music, the environment, everything seemed perfect. I wouldn&rsquo;t change that moment for a single bit. It was one of those nights you wish lasted forever. And through this post, I hope they do.</p>
<p>I will never forget the days we spent there, they were single-handedly the best three days of my entire life. Nothing during it ever felt real and yet everything lives in my head so vividly. And this was the glorious end I was hoping for. I was very happy with the way it ended, being literally on top of the world with the girl of my dreams and overlooking the city we explored and the journeys we took on those days. Saying it was magical is simply not enough.</p>
<p>Thanks, Mom and Dad, for the gift of a lifetime, and an adventure I will never, ever forget.</p>
<p>After contemplating this for a while longer, deciding it was a more than a worthy end to a great story, and getting overly emotional like I am when writing this, we left, and ended our chapter for the day once more.</p>

    <img src="/trip-to-london/shard-top.jpg"  alt="A tiny portion of the view from the top of the Shard"  class="center"  style="border-radius: 8px;"  />


<p>Well, almost ended. As we were heading back, it was still a bit early and we didn&rsquo;t want to waste our final hours in a hotel room moping. So, we did the only thing any sane person would do. We took the subway to the busiest and happiest place we had visited yet, Piccadilly Circus and the neighboring Leicester Square, just to get one final look at the nightlife (and also have dinner, we were starving).</p>
<p>We soaked up more of the London lifestyle, a thing which one would never get bored of, headed back into the tube, crawled back into the hotel one last time from absolutely dead feet, and passed out completely on the bed. This time, sadly, without a real plan for the next day, except waking up early. Way too early.</p>
<h2 id="day-4-the-return">Day 4: The Return</h2>
<p>As the clock struck something like 5:30 A.M, we were up.</p>
<p>Our plane was really, really early, and we still had a subway and a train to take. As we woke up the sky was still pitch black. In the streets, you couldn&rsquo;t hear a thing. Not a single person was around. In a city like this, that is slightly terrifying.</p>
<p>But the really scary part wasn&rsquo;t there being anyone, it was the storm that had formed during the night. The wind was really picking up, lifting traffic cones and nearly taking down fences, it seemed as if London didn&rsquo;t want us to go at all. We made it safely towards the tube, which was, again, completely empty. After a while, a single person came, and that is when it started becoming a bit creepy.</p>
<p>Luckily, soon enough the train arrived, and off we were from that place, for the last time. During the journey, there were mostly workers on their way to work, and along with them, two tourists looking tired as everything, me and Daniela. When we arrived once again at Liverpool Street Station, my godfather was already there, just like in the airport. It seemed like the start of the journey all over again. We waited for a bit, bought our tickets for the train, and this time it was quite early to catch it, with nearly no one else alongside us.</p>
<p>The trip seemed to go fast. We were all talking about what we had seen and heard on those days, me and Daniela talking about the center of London and all that we saw and our amazing plan, and them talking about some beautiful areas in the outskirts that we didn&rsquo;t have the chance to explore (maybe one day we&rsquo;ll go back, who knows).</p>
<p>As soon as the train stopped and we left, the sun was starting to shine once again. But we couldn&rsquo;t see any of it. A huge storm was picking up just outside the airport. Also, we were kind of late. After a bit of frantic running all around it, we finally found where we were supposed to be, made the check-in, and had the chance to lounge around for a bit. We all bought coffee, I bought some crisps with a flavor I had never seen before, and soon enough our flight came up.</p>
<p>Yet another frantic journey to enter, a final bid of farewell to the city that took us in so incredibly well, and off we were, heading back to normality. As it turns out, we were lucky to even get on that flight, because as the storm was really getting crazy we got off, at just the right time. Any longer and it would probably have been canceled.</p>
<p>The little I remember of this flight, I was tired like crazy. I don&rsquo;t recall sleeping, but I wasn&rsquo;t too far from it. After 2:30 hours, we landed safely back in the great city of Porto. My parents were there, and Daniela&rsquo;s dad was not too far off. We all chatted for a bit, shared a few laughs, and then we went our separate ways.</p>
<p>In the 45 minute drive home, I didn&rsquo;t stop talking for a bit. And to tell them everything that happened, I really couldn&rsquo;t. I could have spent entire days talking about it, but my parents had better things to do.</p>
<p>I arrived home, had lunch as it was already getting late, and here comes the real twist of events. This trip ended on the same day the second semester of university started! So we had lunch, I talked a bit more about my journey and they listened, and as soon as we were done, we started unpacking what I brought and packing my suitcase for uni. That day was such a wild ride. I arrived home an hour or two ago and already was I packing for another ride. At least this time we would be much closer to home.</p>
<p>When everything was packed and ready to go, we waited for a few minutes, they drove to the train station, and as soon as they got me back home, they would let me go once more. And the best part of all? I was also going with Daniela on this train! Me heading right back to where we left from, Porto, and she to Aveiro, where she studies.</p>
<p>It seemed as we never really left each other during this small time. Both of us still were smiling and laughing about all that happened. But all that would have to stay put for a while. We had new classes, new schedules, and new challenges to adapt to. And just like that, as the greatest chapter in my life ended, another one began.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 3</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 11:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-3/</guid>
            <description>For the first time since the start of this challenge, I started this week off with a blast. When Monday came, and the big exam was done, I immediately decided it was time for a change. Now that only a single exam remains, and one that I am hoping to be quite the easy challenge, I finally had the time to kill it in my workouts and give my all without the fear of falling behind in university.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the first time since the start of this challenge, I started this week off with a blast. When Monday came, and the big exam was done, I immediately decided it was time for a change. Now that only a single exam remains, and one that I am hoping to be quite the easy challenge, I finally had the time to kill it in my workouts and give my all without the fear of falling behind in university. That translated right away into better performance in the gym from the get-go. Here are some of the highlights from each day:</p>
<h2 id="day-1---the-planning">Day 1 - The planning</h2>
<p>Monday was my long-distance running day, and it turned out to be an absolute blast. Before even starting to work out, I decided that it would be a day of mental rest, as I still had a lot of time to study, and for me, the best mental recovery there is, comes from exercising. For some reason, it always feels like my brain finally shuts down for a while and relaxes when I am running or lifting weights.</p>
<p>Also, I was getting tired of trying to plan my workouts in my notes apps and trying to coordinate everything from there, so I ported everything I had into <a href="https://todoist.com/">Todoist</a>, my to-do app of choice, and made myself a little &ldquo;workout tracker&rdquo;. It is not ideal but for me, it works well enough and I seem to get more done when I can cross everything from my Today view, as it is super satisfying. It was a bit of a rough change and cost me a lot of time from the actual workout, but since I made this day a day off, I quickly stopped worrying about it.</p>
<h2 id="day-2---crushing-leg-day">Day 2 - Crushing Leg Day</h2>
<p>The worst days of the week are without a doubt leg days. Even though I don&rsquo;t actually mind training legs, and there are some exercises that I now do and that I wanted to be doing a long time now, the day after leg day always sucks. To make matters worse, leg days are always the day after running days, so my legs are already sore when I enter the gym. But with my determination for the week, I managed to &ldquo;ignore&rdquo; all that and keep going, which turned out pretty well.</p>
<p>I made some progress on the machine exercises, like leg press and extensions, and for the first time felt I was ready to try to do actual deadlifts and squats with a barbell. Now I can finally try some of the compound lifts that I always wanted to do, but never knew how to do them. Even though I am very weak at them, I feel like I can make good progress if I am consistent.</p>
<h2 id="day-3---maxing-out-reps">Day 3 - Maxing out Reps</h2>
<p>On day 3 I decided I was not making enough progress with my push-ups and sit-ups. I want to be able to do at least 100 push-ups in sets by around week 6 and at the current pace that was not working. So instead of trying to only increase my reps weekly, I decided to increase them daily. And that is how I went from 65 to 70 push-ups in a day. The same thing happened with sit-ups, but progress was much easier. Even though my core hurts almost every day, sit-ups are relatively simple to do and can max them out easily (maybe it is because I am not focusing enough on the core, but the other exercises help a lot with it). As such I can make an evolution every day, which is a great motivation booster for keep crushing these workouts.</p>
<h2 id="day-4---a-more-relaxed-day">Day 4 - A more relaxed day</h2>
<p>Thursday is almost my mid-week rest day. It is only a day for push-ups, pull-ups, sit-ups, and the core routine, with no running or cardio of any form. So even though I still got to grind out 75 push-ups and give my all for the pull-ups, there is not much else after that (the core routine is meant more for stability and balance than actual strength gains). As such, these days are optimal candidates for implementing a stretching routine, which I desperately need (I am the most non-flexible person I know), so it would be a good complement to the strength training.</p>
<h2 id="day-5---a-slight-twist">Day 5 - A slight twist</h2>
<p>Friday was supposed to be my upper body and running day but turned out to be one of the best workouts I ever had. Instead of running alone, the cardio consisted of playing a few hours of futsal with my friends from university. And it also happened that I had my last exam that morning, so I felt even better to go out and do something super fun. It was a blast, we played almost non-stop for 2 hours and a bit, and in the end, everyone was exhausted, but not for one moment did I want to stop. After all that I could barely walk home, much less go to the gym. But the energy expended and work done made it a worthy tradeoff.</p>
<h2 id="day-6---an-absolute-wreck">Day 6 - An absolute wreck</h2>
<p>The aftermath of a day like that, however, is not all that fun. During the night I was still fine, just really tired, but when the morning came it all hit at once. I could barely move a single leg muscle and absolutely everything felt sore. This is what happens when the university work makes me sit down almost the entire day, the muscles start to degrade heavily and weaken a lot. Needless to say, I couldn&rsquo;t go to the gym to do leg day, as I almost couldn&rsquo;t make it out of my bed waking up and had to drag myself out of it. Still, I regret nothing and would play all day again (just let me rest for a few days now).</p>
<h1 id="rounding-out-the-week">Rounding out the week</h1>
<p>All in all, it was one of my most physically active weeks of the year, and one I am very proud of for sticking to so well. I probably wouldn&rsquo;t have done it if my girlfriend didn&rsquo;t motivate me on some days, so kudos to her as well. Now, even though I am still hurt from Friday (I am writing this on Sunday and still can barely walk), I am ready to take on another week that will leave me absolutely wrecked and craving for more, all while developing a great physique along the way. Couldn&rsquo;t ask for a better start to my year. See you later!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 2</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 18:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-2/</guid>
            <description>Week 2 was yet another one of my terrific failures. It seems that the start of this challenge is going to be the worst part of them all. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right that after all the continuous hard work put in during the semester, I still have to complete exams on top of it (which sadly, most of them didn&amp;rsquo;t go as I expected). This little journey is also becoming a bit of a weekly insight into my life which is not the original plan, but one I don&amp;rsquo;t mind at all.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Week 2 was yet another one of my terrific failures. It seems that the start of this challenge is going to be the worst part of them all. And it doesn&rsquo;t feel right that after all the continuous hard work put in during the semester, I still have to complete exams on top of it (which sadly, most of them didn&rsquo;t go as I expected). This little journey is also becoming a bit of a weekly insight into my life which is not the original plan, but one I don&rsquo;t mind at all.</p>
<h1 id="a-new-challenger-appears">A new challenger appears</h1>
<p>After all the hard work that was put into projects, it becomes even more draining to condense the materials of a whole semester of classes and memorize them in two to three days, and then rinse and repeat until all 5 classes are done. This takes its toll on someone. Especially someone like me, who during that time magically became terrible at coordinating his life, and found himself struggling to do anything besides memorizing facts for a whole week. But that made me realize something a bit obvious to some people but for me, it needed to hit me in the face to be noticed.</p>
<h2 id="the-power-of-consistency">The power of consistency</h2>
<p>During my two-day fiestas of memorization, I noticed that when I took things slow and allowed my brain some time to process stuff, I recalled better than when I tried to look at things nonstop and think constantly. It is just like doing exercise. Rest is as important as actual training because it is then that your muscles develop. The brain works in just the same way. So, while for now I can&rsquo;t go back and change my whole semester, I can try to improve forwards. Instead of being the person that never goes to class (something I abused quite heavily this semester), I will be the person that tries in every class to get the essential so that everything is already well understood come exam season.</p>
<p>Notice that I said, &ldquo;I will be the person&rdquo;. This is important. Recently I have learned that to make new habits stick, it is essential to change not only the objective you are headed for, your goals, or in this case, me not having another insomnia-inducing study night, but also what you believe in. It is much easier to stop smoking by saying &ldquo;I am not a smoker&rdquo; than &ldquo;I am trying to quit&rdquo;. One has an identity conflict, and people tend to act according to their identity more than anything else. So if you want to change something in your life, and it is something that will help you a ton, start by changing your identity to be the person who gets what you want. That is what will do this semester. I will be the good student and the fitness dude and will succeed in both (This is the point where the narrator says that I couldn&rsquo;t be more wrong, let&rsquo;s hope he isn&rsquo;t hearing).</p>
<h1 id="in-the-coming-future">In the coming future</h1>
<p>This week made me realize that I wasn&rsquo;t getting my objectives, not because of a simple lack of time or motivation or energy, but a whole infrastructure of small mistakes that I did and lead to this moment. From now on, I won&rsquo;t be that person anymore. Week 3 is going to show just that. Also, when the second semester comes, I will do what I can to try and make the journey as smooth as possible. This includes paying attention to classes, trying to follow a system for learning consistently that works, and overall just dedicating more time to being the person I want to be in the future. It will take some time to plan, but looking at all the tiny things I can improve in life can and will make the difference. So let&rsquo;s get to it. Today marks the start of a new me.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 1</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 11:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-1/</guid>
            <description>I have to be honest, during week one I was terrible. Not because I found the training hard and was constantly sore from doing it, but because I didn&amp;rsquo;t even actually train in most of the days. It felt terrible doing this to myself, even more so when I was just starting and was supposed to at least try in the first week, it didn&amp;rsquo;t go at all according to plan.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have to be honest, during week one I was terrible. Not because I found the training hard and was constantly sore from doing it, but because I didn&rsquo;t even actually train in most of the days. It felt terrible doing this to myself, even more so when I was just starting and was supposed to at least try in the first week, it didn&rsquo;t go at all according to plan. Why did this happen, you ask? Well, its a combination of pressure from the projects at university and an unsuited environment</p>
<h1 id="the-pressure-of-university-projects">The pressure of university projects</h1>
<p>By the time I had planned to start this training, classes were just about to finish. With the end of classes here come two things: the due dates for all projects and the start of exam season. I was prepared for neither of these.</p>
<p>The projects I had been working on them all semester and some of them were going well (two of them were delivered a few days before the due date, and another was just needing some final touches). But the last project, and the worst one of them all, was a total mess. It is really hard to make a project when the assignment in itself is terrible, and it was a horrible project, to begin with, in a class with absolutely no guidance and with bad and borderline stupid requirements, but it is even worse when a project for 2 people was all done by only one. That&rsquo;s what happened to me. The entire semester we had a clear division between what was to be done by who, and all my parts were completed on time and worked (even helping with some things along the way), but everything else never showed up.</p>
<p>That led to a two-day rush to just finish what was possible and try to get as much done to at least come up with a decent thing, also on my own on these times. The result was a near-total burnout and both physical and mental exhaustion. All to at least not straight up fail a terrible project. With all this, I lost two days of working out to make a project I am not even proud of and it only cost my entire willpower to wake up &ldquo;on time&rdquo; and take some time for physical exercise the rest of the week. Nevertheless, I tried to do some exercise the day after this, to try and take my mind off things, but it wasn&rsquo;t the same thing. I wasn&rsquo;t giving it my all, which is detrimental to building muscle.</p>
<p>After all this, I didn&rsquo;t have a lot of time to recover, because straight after the projects were done we had 2 days to study for the upcoming exams, which lead to even more days filled with studying and little to no time for exercise.</p>
<h1 id="not-an-ideal-environment">Not an ideal environment</h1>
<p>The little time I had for actually working out, and with the remaining energy I had, the conditions weren&rsquo;t ideal for a productive &ldquo;gym&rdquo; session. I was with my girlfriend at the time, and we were in her room all day.</p>
<p>Even though Aveiro is a really good place to go out and run or work out, we couldn&rsquo;t do it because of several reasons. So, since going out to train was out of the question, I had to improvise with what I had in the room. It turned out there are a lot of things you can do with a little imagination, like using a filled suitcase for an overhead press, and jugs of water for dumbells, and it would be quite fun to figure out things like that if I had the time and energy to do so.</p>
<p>Figuring out these things when burnt out is, sadly, not ideal. It showed me that I can have a good (but not great) workout whenever and wherever with just a little imagination, but it lead to even more tiredness that I couldn&rsquo;t handle at the time.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>Out of the 6 days that I was supposed to work out, I did it to near completion for 2 days, and a half workout for another. Not the best of starts, that&rsquo;s a fact, but it taught me a lesson from the get-go. The conditions will not be easy at some times, and failure is inevitable when situations overwhelm us. To succeed, it is essential to have good planning and control of the day, and mostly, of ourselves. It is not going to be an easy journey, and now week 2 must start without the proper training, so I will need to give it my all. Let&rsquo;s make it count.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 0</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-0/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-0/</guid>
            <description>Navy SEALs are tough people, there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt about it.
From David Goggins to Jocko Willink and all others, they can inspire everyone to become a better version of themselves. And that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what they did to me. I come from Portugal, but for a period of my life around the time I was 11 and dreamy, I was convinced I would join the SEALs, breeze through training and be a part of the elite, jumping from airplanes in enemy territory and going on crazy missions around the world, just like in the movies.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Navy SEALs are tough people, there&rsquo;s no doubt about it.</p>
<p>From David Goggins to Jocko Willink and all others, they can inspire everyone to become a better version of themselves. And that&rsquo;s exactly what they did to me. I come from Portugal, but for a period of my life around the time I was 11 and dreamy, I was convinced I would join the SEALs, breeze through training and be a part of the elite, jumping from airplanes in enemy territory and going on crazy missions around the world, just like in the movies. That lasted until about the time I found I needed U.S citizenship and good eyesight, two things which I, sadly, lacked.</p>

    <img src="/navy-seal-training-0/seals-training.jpg"  alt="Navy SEALs Training"  class="center"  />


<h1 id="why-be-like-a-navy-seal">Why be like a Navy Seal?</h1>
<p>Whilst the dream of becoming one quickly disappeared, the admiration for what they did persisted. I saw a documentary that showed what they went through Bootcamp and the infamous Hell Week, the physical and mental beating they took, and the way they move on either way, it was amazing to see just what hard work can accomplish. Also, they were insanely physically fit. They were an example of a life with training not only of the body but of the mind as well, having achieved <em>mens sana in corpore sano</em> (a healthy mind in a healthy body). Me, being the short and skinny teenager that I was back then, wished to one day be like that and saw it as something that if they could do, so could I.</p>
<p>And so, a few years later, I set out to do just that.</p>
<h1 id="how-to-train-to-be-a-navy-seal">How to train to be a Navy Seal</h1>
<p>I didn&rsquo;t come to this as an absolute beginner. For about a year I had trained casually and for a while even went to the gym, so I had at least some minimal physical form. Still, nothing could prepare me for what was ahead.</p>
<h2 id="week-0---the-planning">Week 0 - The planning</h2>
<p>The training consisted of a 26-week plan, where each week I would be training 6 times, Monday to Saturday. Every training includes a form of cardio, in the form of either running or swimming, and some weight training to go with it. Here&rsquo;s how it goes:</p>
<h3 id="cardio">Cardio</h3>
<p>Cardio would be divided into 3 sections, differing in intensity and length of training. They are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Long Slow Distance (LSD) training, where you run/swim for a long distance at a slower, but steady pace.</li>
<li>Continuous High Intensity (CHI), where you run/swim for a short distance at a very high intensity.</li>
<li>Interval training, where you combine the two methods above to create changes in pace and intensity in a controlled fashion.</li>
</ul>
<p>Mondays would be for LSD running, Wednesdays for Interval, and Fridays for CHI. Then there came swimming, and that&rsquo;s where the problems began. I don&rsquo;t have a swimming pool I can attend. Sadly, I would not be able to develop my swimming during the training. Whilst I do appreciate the extra rest that I get on those days, it would be fun to complete the entire &ldquo;challenge&rdquo;. But still, I had running, which was hard enough already for someone who sits on a chair all day.</p>
<h3 id="calisthenics">Calisthenics</h3>
<p>The military isn&rsquo;t big on gyms. If you can drop down and give me 20 then why wouldn&rsquo;t you? It is great exercise and best of all, it&rsquo;s free. For a college student like me that instantly sounds super appealing.</p>
<p>As such, for the most part, the major calisthenics exercises performed were the humble push-up, pull-up, and sit-up combo. While it may seem easy, doing 50 push-ups and 50 sit-ups after doing 15 pull-ups is a lot harder than you may think (if you have doubts you go ahead and try it). It was great that the training was based on these exercises because that meant I could perform the majority of them at home. Sadly, I also had no pull-up bar near me, but for that, I had a gym to go to. But why go to a gym if you only intended to do calisthenics, you ask?</p>
<h3 id="strength-training">Strength Training</h3>
<p>For SEALs, doing only calisthenics isn&rsquo;t enough. Whilst training like that can give a lot of benefits, for sheer strength gains, there is nothing like isolated machine and weight work. And for that, you need machines and weights, two things which I don&rsquo;t have at home. Luckily, near my apartment in Porto is a really cool gym, and it is not over the top expensive (unlike the ones in my hometown), so it was a cost that was bearable.</p>
<p>The training here consisted of mostly weight work, and the more complete tried and tested exercises were preferred. For the upper body, things like bench and shoulder press, rows, and lat pulldowns were the main type of exercises, whilst for the lower body it was more machine focused, with things like leg extensions and curls, but also weight work like squats and deadlifts were included.</p>
<p>Time at the gym was meant for time to put on heavy loads and to get maximal strength gains so, for the most part, sets and reps weren&rsquo;t the main factors, but higher weights and perfect repetitions were. Mondays and Fridays were dedicated to the upper body, and Tuesdays and Saturdays were for the lower body, mixed with some of the calisthenics that I already talked about. Wednesdays and Thursdays on the other hand were full-on bodyweight days, which saved me some time on my week for other things as well.</p>
<h3 id="planning-my-day-around-it">Planning my day around it</h3>
<p>At the time of this &ldquo;challenge&rdquo;, I am a college student. This means that my life is already incredibly busy as it is. From going to classes and doing homework and projects, whilst also keeping up with what is being taught and preparing for tests and exams, a good portion of my day is dedicated to working. All around, I spend anywhere from 8 to 12 hours a day on university business. Add to that taking care of my bedroom and cooking (I live with 2 roommates and usually, I am the one who cooks), and there go 3 more hours spent.</p>
<p>From the 24 hours we have in a day if we subtract that plus the 6:30/7 hours I sleep usually (yes I know I should sleep more, it&rsquo;s a struggle), that leaves me with about 6 hours for everything else. Going to university takes about 20/25 minutes, so there goes almost another hour. Take 2 hours for hobbies and winding down at night and it leaves me with around 3 hours a day for exercising and to &ldquo;redistribute&rdquo; through other tasks (things always take longer than we expect). In the end, each day, there are around 2/2:30 hours for me to warm up, workout, and cool down, which is not a lot.</p>
<p>Fitting this at night would not be a good idea, as it would impact my already poor sleep. In the middle of the morning is nearly impossible because of university and during the afternoon it wouldn&rsquo;t be productive, as I would need to stop working and switch context to working out and then go back to work, which goes against the idea of deep work, which for me is essential.</p>
<p>That leaves me with one option: Working out before university starts, early in the morning. As you can imagine, I hate waking up early, and anything before 8 for me is already early, so when I figured out that to have time for everything I would need to wake up at 6, and sometimes even 5:30, I was devastated. This, for me, was without a doubt the hardest part. Not only waking up at 5:30 but also going to sleep at like 22:30 or 23:00, to get at least 7 hours of sleep each night. It took a lot of incremental changes to get up to the point where I can be semi-awake at those early hours, and even now beginning this &ldquo;challenge&rdquo; is a struggle, but it is one I have since become accustomed to.</p>
<h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h1>
<p>This is much more than a &ldquo;30 days of something challenge&rdquo;, it is a commitment to half a year of consistent dedication to physically and mentally challenging training. It is a complete context switch from the sedentary life I had so far just doing university work. But it is a necessary change, and it is a step in the right direction for a healthier, more disciplined, and overall better life. And it is just getting started. Stay tuned, as next week I will recap what the first week of training was like. And if you are also <del>crazy</del> ambitious enough to do this, join me and do share your progress with me as well. But enough talking, now it is time to go out and do it. Or, as the incredible Jocko Willink said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Go down swinging. And I&rsquo;ll tell you: if you fight with all you have, more often than not, you won&rsquo;t go down at all. You will win</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Resume</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/resume/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 19:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/resume/</guid>
            <description>If you prefer a PDF version, you can find one here.
Experience Summary I am a third-year student currently getting a bachelor’s degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering. I love getting involved in new environments and meeting new people, because only then can I develop as a person and reach new heights.
During the summer of 2021, to challenge myself, I did a small internship at a company in my hometown, where I dealt with completely different circumstances compared to the ones faced in university, and had to learn new skills by myself, which in turn greatly improved my ability to learn on the fly and become even more passionate about this field.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you prefer a PDF version, you can find one <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1KwOkKca15Qu0sQ3muh21ADBqYabnHrEr/view?usp=sharing">here</a>.</p>
<h1 id="experience-summary">Experience Summary</h1>
<p>I am a third-year student currently getting a bachelor’s degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering. I love getting involved in new environments and meeting new people, because only then can I develop as a person and reach new heights.</p>
<p>During the summer of 2021, to challenge myself, I did a small internship at a company in my hometown, where I dealt with completely different circumstances compared to the ones faced in university, and had to learn new skills by myself, which in turn greatly improved my ability to learn on the fly and become even more passionate about this field.</p>
<p>And now, during Christmas, my grandmother told me to choose a gift, and so I chose this! It is a great way to learn about a field I am starting to love more and more, and it is a great way to train and have a sandbox where I can try new things.</p>
<h1 id="skills">Skills</h1>
<p><strong>Levels</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 - Curious about, eager to learn</li>
<li>2 - Begginer and Academic training only</li>
<li>3 - Small Projects and/or Internships</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="programming">Programming</h2>
<p>These are the languages I know best:</p>
<ul>
<li>HTML, CSS and JavaScript - 3</li>
<li>C# - 3</li>
<li>C/C++ - 2</li>
<li>Java - 2</li>
<li>PHP - 2</li>
<li>PostgreSQL and SQLite - 2</li>
<li>Haskell - 2</li>
<li>Python - 2</li>
<li>TypeScript - 1</li>
<li>Rust - 1</li>
<li>Go - 1</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="operating-systems">Operating Systems</h2>
<ul>
<li>Linux (Arch Linux, Ubuntu) - 3</li>
<li>Windows 10 - 3</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="frameworks">Frameworks</h2>
<ul>
<li>Bootstrap - 3</li>
<li>.NET - 3</li>
<li>Laravel - 2</li>
<li>Angular - 1</li>
<li>NestJs - 1</li>
<li>React - 1</li>
<li>TailwindCSS - 1</li>
<li>Flutter - 1</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="tools-i-use">Tools I use</h2>
<ul>
<li>Emacs (Doom Emacs) - 2</li>
<li>VSCode - 2</li>
<li>Vim (NeoVim) - 2</li>
<li>Git/Github/GitLab 2</li>
<li>Hugo - 2</li>
<li>Figma - 1</li>
<li>LaTeX - 1</li>
<li>Visual Studio - 3</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="projects">Projects</h1>
<h2 id="websystems---full-stack-web-developer">Websystems - Full Stack Web Developer</h2>
<h4 id="from-july-2021-to-september-2021">From July 2021 to September 2021</h4>
<h4 id="description">Description</h4>
<p>The project intended to expand their administration dashboard, which was used to monitor assets about their clients, as well as serving as a task manager for the whole Websystems team.</p>
<p>My goal was to add the ability to store information about the hardware and software of all the different clients, namely their workstations, servers, printers, among many others, integrate with the rest of the information and create a new section in the dashboard for display.</p>
<p>To do this I had to update the database to include the new tables, develop the front-end for presentation and easy retrieval of the information, and the back-end for processing all of the information sent, using an MVC architecture as a basis for the structure.</p>
<h4 id="technologies-used">Technologies used</h4>
<ul>
<li>C# - Page Controllers and Models created using an Object Relational Mapper.</li>
<li>ASP.NET Framework - Facilitating development of the application with built-in templates and tools.</li>
<li>Microsoft SQL Server - DBMS used to store the information.</li>
<li>HTML with Razor Templating Engine - Views and presentation of the information.</li>
<li>CSS and JavaScript - Visual styling and animations in the presented page.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="personal---installing-and-configuring-arch-linux">Personal - Installing and Configuring Arch Linux</h2>
<h4 id="from-february-2021-to-march-2021">From February 2021 to March 2021</h4>
<h4 id="description-1">Description</h4>
<p>Installed and customized Arch Linux from scratch to learn more about how the operating systems work and have full control over my computing experience.</p>
<p>Having used Ubuntu for some university work, I became fascinated seeing what was possible to do in a Linux computer and how efficient some desktops were. So, during a vacation period, I created a second partition in my computer and installed Arch Linux, customizing it to fit my needs. After some long hours reading documentation, erasing and rewriting partitions and even starting completely from scratch several times, victory was finally achieved.</p>
<p>The result is a desktop that works how I want it and allows me to be much more efficient, aside from being a much better environment to work on. Also, I now have complete knowledge of what is installed in my computer and how everything works and interacts with it, giving me a greater knowledge about the different components, and lighting up a passion for keeping on learning and discovering more about this field. I may even write a post about it someday! 👀</p>
<h4 id="technologies-used-1">Technologies used</h4>
<ul>
<li>Arch Linux - Operating system of a certain complexity but not too exaggerated.</li>
<li>Git - Management tool used for installing some extra packages not available in repositories.</li>
<li>Vim and Doom Emacs - Text editors used for setting up the system (and to configure themselves).</li>
<li>BSPWM - Window manager responsible for desktop configuration.</li>
<li>SXHKD - Program responsible for managing key binds that are used in the system.</li>
<li>Polybar - System bar with a set of useful widgets and information.</li>
<li>Rofi - App Launcher and System Control Widgets.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="personal---this-website">Personal - This website!</h2>
<h4 id="from-december-2021-to-today">From December 2021 to Today</h4>
<h4 id="description-2">Description</h4>
<p>Built my personal website and hosted on Github Pages, using a custom domain.</p>
<p>I always wanted a website, a place to share my thoughts with the world and one where I can build the experience users have when they enter. Finally, this Christmas, it happened (thanks Grandma).</p>
<p>To start, my grandma gifted me the domain. I had built some minor websites for university, but nothing like this. Since I never had built anything like this, I wanted to start by something small, in this case with a static website and a static website generator. I chose Hugo because it had some awesome themes and the setup was super quick. In the future I would love to build my own website template, but built from the ground up. Since I discovered the world of web development, Angular has always fascinated me (much more so than React). So stick around because in the future this website will probably be rebuilt with Angular and my very own CDN (it sounds impossible right now but a person can dream).</p>
<p>Even though it is not perfect, I have learned a great deal from assembling this, from linking domain names and redirects, SSL certificates, web hosting, and the art of publishing and keeping the local result the same as the remote one (an art that I learned by failing a lot of times, sadly). I also gained knowledge about the Jamstack and its benefits to the web (it is what I am using right now!), and finally, I gained a love for web development and a desire to learn a lot more than the small amount I know now. Hopefully in the future this will be one of my best projects!</p>
<h4 id="technologies-used-2">Technologies used</h4>
<ul>
<li>Hugo - Static Website Generator used.</li>
<li>Github Pages - Web host, great for static websites.</li>
<li>Doom Emacs - Text editor used for writing posts.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rhazdon/hugo-theme-hello-friend-ng">Hello-friend-ng</a> - Theme used to style the website.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="education">Education</h1>
<h2 id="july-2022--bachelors-degree">July 2022 – Bachelor&rsquo;s Degree</h2>
<h4 id="informatics-and-computer-engineering">Informatics and Computer Engineering</h4>
<h4 id="faculty-of-engineering-of-the-university-of-porto-feup">Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto (FEUP)</h4>
<h2 id="june-2019--high-school">June 2019 – High School</h2>
<h4 id="curso-científico-humanístico-de-ciências-e-tecnologias">Curso Científico-Humanístico de Ciências e Tecnologias</h4>
<h4 id="escola-secundária-de-barcelos">Escola Secundária de Barcelos</h4>
<h1 id="languages">Languages</h1>
<h3 id="portuguese">Portuguese:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Understanding: Native.</li>
<li>Speaking: Native.</li>
<li>Writing: Native.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="english">English</h3>
<ul>
<li>Understanding: C2 (Advanced).</li>
<li>Speaking: B2 (Independent).</li>
<li>Writing: C2 (Advanced).</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hi guys</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 17:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</guid>
            <description>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to try, right?
That&amp;rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&amp;rsquo;m fine).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&rsquo;t hurt to try, right?</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&rsquo;m fine).</p>
<p>You can find me in either Barcelos or Porto, depending on whether I am at university or chilling during my vacations.</p>
<h1 id="education">Education</h1>
<p>I am studying Informatics and Computer Engineering in <a href="https://fe.up.pt">FEUP</a> for a Bachelors degree, but I do intend on getting a Masters after it. It has been a crazy wild ride really, and I am loving it.</p>
<p>Before this, during high school, I went to Escola de Secundária de Barcelos, where I graduated with an 18.5 out of 20. Everyone&rsquo;s experience in high school is different but I think some of the best years of my life where spent in this school, maybe one day I&rsquo;ll even write about them.</p>
<h1 id="fun-stuff-i-like-doing">Fun Stuff I like doing</h1>
<p>The thing I most enjoy doing in this world is definitely to travel (bonus points if I go with my girlfriend). If it was possible, I would love to one day visit every country in the world at least once, kind of like <a href="https://onestep4ward.com/my-journey-to-every-country-in-the-world-country-list-and-faq/">this guy did</a>, even though that would take a lifetime to complete.</p>
<p>If I am forced to be at home, then my favorite thing in the world is definitely tinkering with my computer, especially the software department (I am studying software engineering after all). Maybe one day I will even show you my setup. When I want to go analog though, I usually try to read some books on how I can improve my life (I love stuff about habit-building and productivity in general), and recently I have discovered that I love learning new languages, and the less usual the better. Currently, I know Portuguese (duh) and English, and I am trying to learn Norwegian. Also I intend to one day expand to a language from out of Europe, as an extra challenge.</p>
<p>Finally, I am a gamer at heart. Ever since I first started playing on my PlayStation when I was like 10 and to this day, I have loved the experience that only games can give you. One of my favorite ways to spend time is playing TFT with my girlfriend, or exploring the Nordic myths and legends first-hand in God of War.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>As you can probably see I can find things that fascinate me in just about everything. If that is a blessing or a curse is up to you, but for me, it means that there will never be a dull moment in my life, and that I will always have something fun to talk about, be it with my lovely girlfriend, my family, my friends, and now with anyone that stumbles across this little piece of the internet. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
