<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</title>
        <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 11:58:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 3</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 11:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-3/</guid>
            <description>For the first time since the start of this challenge, I started this week off with a blast. When Monday came, and the big exam was done, I immediately decided it was time for a change. Now that only a single exam remains, and one that I am hoping to be quite the easy challenge, I finally had the time to kill it in my workouts and give my all without the fear of falling behind in university.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the first time since the start of this challenge, I started this week off with a blast. When Monday came, and the big exam was done, I immediately decided it was time for a change. Now that only a single exam remains, and one that I am hoping to be quite the easy challenge, I finally had the time to kill it in my workouts and give my all without the fear of falling behind in university. That translated right away into better performance in the gym from the get-go. Here are some of the highlights from each day:</p>
<h2 id="day-1---the-planning">Day 1 - The planning</h2>
<p>Monday was my long-distance running day, and it turned out to be an absolute blast. Before even starting to work out, I decided that it would be a day of mental rest, as I still had a lot of time to study, and for me, the best mental recovery there is, comes from exercising. For some reason, it always feels like my brain finally shuts down for a while and relaxes when I am running or lifting weights.</p>
<p>Also, I was getting tired of trying to plan my workouts in my notes apps and trying to coordinate everything from there, so I ported everything I had into <a href="https://todoist.com/">Todoist</a>, my to-do app of choice, and made myself a little &ldquo;workout tracker&rdquo;. It is not ideal but for me, it works well enough and I seem to get more done when I can cross everything from my Today view, as it is super satisfying. It was a bit of a rough change and cost me a lot of time from the actual workout, but since I made this day a day off, I quickly stopped worrying about it.</p>
<h2 id="day-2---crushing-leg-day">Day 2 - Crushing Leg Day</h2>
<p>The worst days of the week are without a doubt leg days. Even though I don&rsquo;t actually mind training legs, and there are some exercises that I now do and that I wanted to be doing a long time now, the day after leg day always sucks. To make matters worse, leg days are always the day after running days, so my legs are already sore when I enter the gym. But with my determination for the week, I managed to &ldquo;ignore&rdquo; all that and keep going, which turned out pretty well.</p>
<p>I made some progress on the machine exercises, like leg press and extensions, and for the first time felt I was ready to try to do actual deadlifts and squats with a barbell. Now I can finally try some of the compound lifts that I always wanted to do, but never knew how to do them. Even though I am very weak at them, I feel like I can make good progress if I am consistent.</p>
<h2 id="day-3---maxing-out-reps">Day 3 - Maxing out Reps</h2>
<p>On day 3 I decided I was not making enough progress with my push-ups and sit-ups. I want to be able to do at least 100 push-ups in sets by around week 6 and at the current pace that was not working. So instead of trying to only increase my reps weekly, I decided to increase them daily. And that is how I went from 65 to 70 push-ups in a day. The same thing happened with sit-ups, but progress was much easier. Even though my core hurts almost every day, sit-ups are relatively simple to do and can max them out easily (maybe it is because I am not focusing enough on the core, but the other exercises help a lot with it). As such I can make an evolution every day, which is a great motivation booster for keep crushing these workouts.</p>
<h2 id="day-4---a-more-relaxed-day">Day 4 - A more relaxed day</h2>
<p>Thursday is almost my mid-week rest day. It is only a day for push-ups, pull-ups, sit-ups, and the core routine, with no running or cardio of any form. So even though I still got to grind out 75 push-ups and give my all for the pull-ups, there is not much else after that (the core routine is meant more for stability and balance than actual strength gains). As such, these days are optimal candidates for implementing a stretching routine, which I desperately need (I am the most non-flexible person I know), so it would be a good complement to the strength training.</p>
<h2 id="day-5---a-slight-twist">Day 5 - A slight twist</h2>
<p>Friday was supposed to be my upper body and running day but turned out to be one of the best workouts I ever had. Instead of running alone, the cardio consisted of playing a few hours of futsal with my friends from university. And it also happened that I had my last exam that morning, so I felt even better to go out and do something super fun. It was a blast, we played almost non-stop for 2 hours and a bit, and in the end, everyone was exhausted, but not for one moment did I want to stop. After all that I could barely walk home, much less go to the gym. But the energy expended and work done made it a worthy tradeoff.</p>
<h2 id="day-6---an-absolute-wreck">Day 6 - An absolute wreck</h2>
<p>The aftermath of a day like that, however, is not all that fun. During the night I was still fine, just really tired, but when the morning came it all hit at once. I could barely move a single leg muscle and absolutely everything felt sore. This is what happens when the university work makes me sit down almost the entire day, the muscles start to degrade heavily and weaken a lot. Needless to say, I couldn&rsquo;t go to the gym to do leg day, as I almost couldn&rsquo;t make it out of my bed waking up and had to drag myself out of it. Still, I regret nothing and would play all day again (just let me rest for a few days now).</p>
<h1 id="rounding-out-the-week">Rounding out the week</h1>
<p>All in all, it was one of my most physically active weeks of the year, and one I am very proud of for sticking to so well. I probably wouldn&rsquo;t have done it if my girlfriend didn&rsquo;t motivate me on some days, so kudos to her as well. Now, even though I am still hurt from Friday (I am writing this on Sunday and still can barely walk), I am ready to take on another week that will leave me absolutely wrecked and craving for more, all while developing a great physique along the way. Couldn&rsquo;t ask for a better start to my year. See you later!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 2</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 18:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-2/</guid>
            <description>Week 2 was yet another one of my terrific failures. It seems that the start of this challenge is going to be the worst part of them all. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right that after all the continuous hard work put in during the semester, I still have to complete exams on top of it (which sadly, most of them didn&amp;rsquo;t go as I expected). This little journey is also becoming a bit of a weekly insight into my life which is not the original plan, but one I don&amp;rsquo;t mind at all.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Week 2 was yet another one of my terrific failures. It seems that the start of this challenge is going to be the worst part of them all. And it doesn&rsquo;t feel right that after all the continuous hard work put in during the semester, I still have to complete exams on top of it (which sadly, most of them didn&rsquo;t go as I expected). This little journey is also becoming a bit of a weekly insight into my life which is not the original plan, but one I don&rsquo;t mind at all.</p>
<h1 id="a-new-challenger-appears">A new challenger appears</h1>
<p>After all the hard work that was put into projects, it becomes even more draining to condense the materials of a whole semester of classes and memorize them in two to three days, and then rinse and repeat until all 5 classes are done. This takes its toll on someone. Especially someone like me, who during that time magically became terrible at coordinating his life, and found himself struggling to do anything besides memorizing facts for a whole week. But that made me realize something a bit obvious to some people but for me, it needed to hit me in the face to be noticed.</p>
<h2 id="the-power-of-consistency">The power of consistency</h2>
<p>During my two-day fiestas of memorization, I noticed that when I took things slow and allowed my brain some time to process stuff, I recalled better than when I tried to look at things nonstop and think constantly. It is just like doing exercise. Rest is as important as actual training because it is then that your muscles develop. The brain works in just the same way. So, while for now I can&rsquo;t go back and change my whole semester, I can try to improve forwards. Instead of being the person that never goes to class (something I abused quite heavily this semester), I will be the person that tries in every class to get the essential so that everything is already well understood come exam season.</p>
<p>Notice that I said, &ldquo;I will be the person&rdquo;. This is important. Recently I have learned that to make new habits stick, it is essential to change not only the objective you are headed for, your goals, or in this case, me not having another insomnia-inducing study night, but also what you believe in. It is much easier to stop smoking by saying &ldquo;I am not a smoker&rdquo; than &ldquo;I am trying to quit&rdquo;. One has an identity conflict, and people tend to act according to their identity more than anything else. So if you want to change something in your life, and it is something that will help you a ton, start by changing your identity to be the person who gets what you want. That is what will do this semester. I will be the good student and the fitness dude and will succeed in both (This is the point where the narrator says that I couldn&rsquo;t be more wrong, let&rsquo;s hope he isn&rsquo;t hearing).</p>
<h1 id="in-the-coming-future">In the coming future</h1>
<p>This week made me realize that I wasn&rsquo;t getting my objectives, not because of a simple lack of time or motivation or energy, but a whole infrastructure of small mistakes that I did and lead to this moment. From now on, I won&rsquo;t be that person anymore. Week 3 is going to show just that. Also, when the second semester comes, I will do what I can to try and make the journey as smooth as possible. This includes paying attention to classes, trying to follow a system for learning consistently that works, and overall just dedicating more time to being the person I want to be in the future. It will take some time to plan, but looking at all the tiny things I can improve in life can and will make the difference. So let&rsquo;s get to it. Today marks the start of a new me.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 1</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 11:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-1/</guid>
            <description>I have to be honest, during week one I was terrible. Not because I found the training hard and was constantly sore from doing it, but because I didn&amp;rsquo;t even actually train in most of the days. It felt terrible doing this to myself, even more so when I was just starting and was supposed to at least try in the first week, it didn&amp;rsquo;t go at all according to plan.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have to be honest, during week one I was terrible. Not because I found the training hard and was constantly sore from doing it, but because I didn&rsquo;t even actually train in most of the days. It felt terrible doing this to myself, even more so when I was just starting and was supposed to at least try in the first week, it didn&rsquo;t go at all according to plan. Why did this happen, you ask? Well, its a combination of pressure from the projects at university and an unsuited environment</p>
<h1 id="the-pressure-of-university-projects">The pressure of university projects</h1>
<p>By the time I had planned to start this training, classes were just about to finish. With the end of classes here come two things: the due dates for all projects and the start of exam season. I was prepared for neither of these.</p>
<p>The projects I had been working on them all semester and some of them were going well (two of them were delivered a few days before the due date, and another was just needing some final touches). But the last project, and the worst one of them all, was a total mess. It is really hard to make a project when the assignment in itself is terrible, and it was a horrible project, to begin with, in a class with absolutely no guidance and with bad and borderline stupid requirements, but it is even worse when a project for 2 people was all done by only one. That&rsquo;s what happened to me. The entire semester we had a clear division between what was to be done by who, and all my parts were completed on time and worked (even helping with some things along the way), but everything else never showed up.</p>
<p>That led to a two-day rush to just finish what was possible and try to get as much done to at least come up with a decent thing, also on my own on these times. The result was a near-total burnout and both physical and mental exhaustion. All to at least not straight up fail a terrible project. With all this, I lost two days of working out to make a project I am not even proud of and it only cost my entire willpower to wake up &ldquo;on time&rdquo; and take some time for physical exercise the rest of the week. Nevertheless, I tried to do some exercise the day after this, to try and take my mind off things, but it wasn&rsquo;t the same thing. I wasn&rsquo;t giving it my all, which is detrimental to building muscle.</p>
<p>After all this, I didn&rsquo;t have a lot of time to recover, because straight after the projects were done we had 2 days to study for the upcoming exams, which lead to even more days filled with studying and little to no time for exercise.</p>
<h1 id="not-an-ideal-environment">Not an ideal environment</h1>
<p>The little time I had for actually working out, and with the remaining energy I had, the conditions weren&rsquo;t ideal for a productive &ldquo;gym&rdquo; session. I was with my girlfriend at the time, and we were in her room all day.</p>
<p>Even though Aveiro is a really good place to go out and run or work out, we couldn&rsquo;t do it because of several reasons. So, since going out to train was out of the question, I had to improvise with what I had in the room. It turned out there are a lot of things you can do with a little imagination, like using a filled suitcase for an overhead press, and jugs of water for dumbells, and it would be quite fun to figure out things like that if I had the time and energy to do so.</p>
<p>Figuring out these things when burnt out is, sadly, not ideal. It showed me that I can have a good (but not great) workout whenever and wherever with just a little imagination, but it lead to even more tiredness that I couldn&rsquo;t handle at the time.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>Out of the 6 days that I was supposed to work out, I did it to near completion for 2 days, and a half workout for another. Not the best of starts, that&rsquo;s a fact, but it taught me a lesson from the get-go. The conditions will not be easy at some times, and failure is inevitable when situations overwhelm us. To succeed, it is essential to have good planning and control of the day, and mostly, of ourselves. It is not going to be an easy journey, and now week 2 must start without the proper training, so I will need to give it my all. Let&rsquo;s make it count.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 0</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-0/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-0/</guid>
            <description>Navy SEALs are tough people, there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt about it.
From David Goggins to Jocko Willink and all others, they can inspire everyone to become a better version of themselves. And that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what they did to me. I come from Portugal, but for a period of my life around the time I was 11 and dreamy, I was convinced I would join the SEALs, breeze through training and be a part of the elite, jumping from airplanes in enemy territory and going on crazy missions around the world, just like in the movies.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Navy SEALs are tough people, there&rsquo;s no doubt about it.</p>
<p>From David Goggins to Jocko Willink and all others, they can inspire everyone to become a better version of themselves. And that&rsquo;s exactly what they did to me. I come from Portugal, but for a period of my life around the time I was 11 and dreamy, I was convinced I would join the SEALs, breeze through training and be a part of the elite, jumping from airplanes in enemy territory and going on crazy missions around the world, just like in the movies. That lasted until about the time I found I needed U.S citizenship and good eyesight, two things which I, sadly, lacked.</p>

    <img src="/navy-seal-training-0/seals-training.jpg"  alt="Navy SEALs Training"  class="center"  />


<h1 id="why-be-like-a-navy-seal">Why be like a Navy Seal?</h1>
<p>Whilst the dream of becoming one quickly disappeared, the admiration for what they did persisted. I saw a documentary that showed what they went through Bootcamp and the infamous Hell Week, the physical and mental beating they took, and the way they move on either way, it was amazing to see just what hard work can accomplish. Also, they were insanely physically fit. They were an example of a life with training not only of the body but of the mind as well, having achieved <em>mens sana in corpore sano</em> (a healthy mind in a healthy body). Me, being the short and skinny teenager that I was back then, wished to one day be like that and saw it as something that if they could do, so could I.</p>
<p>And so, a few years later, I set out to do just that.</p>
<h1 id="how-to-train-to-be-a-navy-seal">How to train to be a Navy Seal</h1>
<p>I didn&rsquo;t come to this as an absolute beginner. For about a year I had trained casually and for a while even went to the gym, so I had at least some minimal physical form. Still, nothing could prepare me for what was ahead.</p>
<h2 id="week-0---the-planning">Week 0 - The planning</h2>
<p>The training consisted of a 26-week plan, where each week I would be training 6 times, Monday to Saturday. Every training includes a form of cardio, in the form of either running or swimming, and some weight training to go with it. Here&rsquo;s how it goes:</p>
<h3 id="cardio">Cardio</h3>
<p>Cardio would be divided into 3 sections, differing in intensity and length of training. They are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Long Slow Distance (LSD) training, where you run/swim for a long distance at a slower, but steady pace.</li>
<li>Continuous High Intensity (CHI), where you run/swim for a short distance at a very high intensity.</li>
<li>Interval training, where you combine the two methods above to create changes in pace and intensity in a controlled fashion.</li>
</ul>
<p>Mondays would be for LSD running, Wednesdays for Interval, and Fridays for CHI. Then there came swimming, and that&rsquo;s where the problems began. I don&rsquo;t have a swimming pool I can attend. Sadly, I would not be able to develop my swimming during the training. Whilst I do appreciate the extra rest that I get on those days, it would be fun to complete the entire &ldquo;challenge&rdquo;. But still, I had running, which was hard enough already for someone who sits on a chair all day.</p>
<h3 id="calisthenics">Calisthenics</h3>
<p>The military isn&rsquo;t big on gyms. If you can drop down and give me 20 then why wouldn&rsquo;t you? It is great exercise and best of all, it&rsquo;s free. For a college student like me that instantly sounds super appealing.</p>
<p>As such, for the most part, the major calisthenics exercises performed were the humble push-up, pull-up, and sit-up combo. While it may seem easy, doing 50 push-ups and 50 sit-ups after doing 15 pull-ups is a lot harder than you may think (if you have doubts you go ahead and try it). It was great that the training was based on these exercises because that meant I could perform the majority of them at home. Sadly, I also had no pull-up bar near me, but for that, I had a gym to go to. But why go to a gym if you only intended to do calisthenics, you ask?</p>
<h3 id="strength-training">Strength Training</h3>
<p>For SEALs, doing only calisthenics isn&rsquo;t enough. Whilst training like that can give a lot of benefits, for sheer strength gains, there is nothing like isolated machine and weight work. And for that, you need machines and weights, two things which I don&rsquo;t have at home. Luckily, near my apartment in Porto is a really cool gym, and it is not over the top expensive (unlike the ones in my hometown), so it was a cost that was bearable.</p>
<p>The training here consisted of mostly weight work, and the more complete tried and tested exercises were preferred. For the upper body, things like bench and shoulder press, rows, and lat pulldowns were the main type of exercises, whilst for the lower body it was more machine focused, with things like leg extensions and curls, but also weight work like squats and deadlifts were included.</p>
<p>Time at the gym was meant for time to put on heavy loads and to get maximal strength gains so, for the most part, sets and reps weren&rsquo;t the main factors, but higher weights and perfect repetitions were. Mondays and Fridays were dedicated to the upper body, and Tuesdays and Saturdays were for the lower body, mixed with some of the calisthenics that I already talked about. Wednesdays and Thursdays on the other hand were full-on bodyweight days, which saved me some time on my week for other things as well.</p>
<h3 id="planning-my-day-around-it">Planning my day around it</h3>
<p>At the time of this &ldquo;challenge&rdquo;, I am a college student. This means that my life is already incredibly busy as it is. From going to classes and doing homework and projects, whilst also keeping up with what is being taught and preparing for tests and exams, a good portion of my day is dedicated to working. All around, I spend anywhere from 8 to 12 hours a day on university business. Add to that taking care of my bedroom and cooking (I live with 2 roommates and usually, I am the one who cooks), and there go 3 more hours spent.</p>
<p>From the 24 hours we have in a day if we subtract that plus the 6:30/7 hours I sleep usually (yes I know I should sleep more, it&rsquo;s a struggle), that leaves me with about 6 hours for everything else. Going to university takes about 20/25 minutes, so there goes almost another hour. Take 2 hours for hobbies and winding down at night and it leaves me with around 3 hours a day for exercising and to &ldquo;redistribute&rdquo; through other tasks (things always take longer than we expect). In the end, each day, there are around 2/2:30 hours for me to warm up, workout, and cool down, which is not a lot.</p>
<p>Fitting this at night would not be a good idea, as it would impact my already poor sleep. In the middle of the morning is nearly impossible because of university and during the afternoon it wouldn&rsquo;t be productive, as I would need to stop working and switch context to working out and then go back to work, which goes against the idea of deep work, which for me is essential.</p>
<p>That leaves me with one option: Working out before university starts, early in the morning. As you can imagine, I hate waking up early, and anything before 8 for me is already early, so when I figured out that to have time for everything I would need to wake up at 6, and sometimes even 5:30, I was devastated. This, for me, was without a doubt the hardest part. Not only waking up at 5:30 but also going to sleep at like 22:30 or 23:00, to get at least 7 hours of sleep each night. It took a lot of incremental changes to get up to the point where I can be semi-awake at those early hours, and even now beginning this &ldquo;challenge&rdquo; is a struggle, but it is one I have since become accustomed to.</p>
<h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h1>
<p>This is much more than a &ldquo;30 days of something challenge&rdquo;, it is a commitment to half a year of consistent dedication to physically and mentally challenging training. It is a complete context switch from the sedentary life I had so far just doing university work. But it is a necessary change, and it is a step in the right direction for a healthier, more disciplined, and overall better life. And it is just getting started. Stay tuned, as next week I will recap what the first week of training was like. And if you are also <del>crazy</del> ambitious enough to do this, join me and do share your progress with me as well. But enough talking, now it is time to go out and do it. Or, as the incredible Jocko Willink said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Go down swinging. And I&rsquo;ll tell you: if you fight with all you have, more often than not, you won&rsquo;t go down at all. You will win</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Resume</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/resume/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 19:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/resume/</guid>
            <description>If you prefer a PDF version, you can find one here.
Experience Summary I am a third-year student currently getting a bachelor’s degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering. I love getting involved in new environments and meeting new people, because only then can I develop as a person and reach new heights.
During the summer of 2021, to challenge myself, I did a small internship at a company in my hometown, where I dealt with completely different circumstances compared to the ones faced in university, and had to learn new skills by myself, which in turn greatly improved my ability to learn on the fly and become even more passionate about this field.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you prefer a PDF version, you can find one <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1KwOkKca15Qu0sQ3muh21ADBqYabnHrEr/view?usp=sharing">here</a>.</p>
<h1 id="experience-summary">Experience Summary</h1>
<p>I am a third-year student currently getting a bachelor’s degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering. I love getting involved in new environments and meeting new people, because only then can I develop as a person and reach new heights.</p>
<p>During the summer of 2021, to challenge myself, I did a small internship at a company in my hometown, where I dealt with completely different circumstances compared to the ones faced in university, and had to learn new skills by myself, which in turn greatly improved my ability to learn on the fly and become even more passionate about this field.</p>
<p>And now, during Christmas, my grandmother told me to choose a gift, and so I chose this! It is a great way to learn about a field I am starting to love more and more, and it is a great way to train and have a sandbox where I can try new things.</p>
<h1 id="skills">Skills</h1>
<p><strong>Levels</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 - Curious about, eager to learn</li>
<li>2 - Begginer and Academic training only</li>
<li>3 - Small Projects and/or Internships</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="programming">Programming</h2>
<p>These are the languages I know best:</p>
<ul>
<li>HTML, CSS and JavaScript - 3</li>
<li>C# - 3</li>
<li>C/C++ - 2</li>
<li>Java - 2</li>
<li>PHP - 2</li>
<li>PostgreSQL and SQLite - 2</li>
<li>Haskell - 2</li>
<li>Python - 2</li>
<li>TypeScript - 1</li>
<li>Rust - 1</li>
<li>Go - 1</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="operating-systems">Operating Systems</h2>
<ul>
<li>Linux (Arch Linux, Ubuntu) - 3</li>
<li>Windows 10 - 3</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="frameworks">Frameworks</h2>
<ul>
<li>Bootstrap - 3</li>
<li>.NET - 3</li>
<li>Laravel - 2</li>
<li>Angular - 1</li>
<li>NestJs - 1</li>
<li>React - 1</li>
<li>TailwindCSS - 1</li>
<li>Flutter - 1</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="tools-i-use">Tools I use</h2>
<ul>
<li>Emacs (Doom Emacs) - 2</li>
<li>VSCode - 2</li>
<li>Vim (NeoVim) - 2</li>
<li>Git/Github/GitLab 2</li>
<li>Hugo - 2</li>
<li>Figma - 1</li>
<li>LaTeX - 1</li>
<li>Visual Studio - 3</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="projects">Projects</h1>
<h2 id="websystems---full-stack-web-developer">Websystems - Full Stack Web Developer</h2>
<h4 id="from-july-2021-to-september-2021">From July 2021 to September 2021</h4>
<h4 id="description">Description</h4>
<p>The project intended to expand their administration dashboard, which was used to monitor assets about their clients, as well as serving as a task manager for the whole Websystems team.</p>
<p>My goal was to add the ability to store information about the hardware and software of all the different clients, namely their workstations, servers, printers, among many others, integrate with the rest of the information and create a new section in the dashboard for display.</p>
<p>To do this I had to update the database to include the new tables, develop the front-end for presentation and easy retrieval of the information, and the back-end for processing all of the information sent, using an MVC architecture as a basis for the structure.</p>
<h4 id="technologies-used">Technologies used</h4>
<ul>
<li>C# - Page Controllers and Models created using an Object Relational Mapper.</li>
<li>ASP.NET Framework - Facilitating development of the application with built-in templates and tools.</li>
<li>Microsoft SQL Server - DBMS used to store the information.</li>
<li>HTML with Razor Templating Engine - Views and presentation of the information.</li>
<li>CSS and JavaScript - Visual styling and animations in the presented page.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="personal---installing-and-configuring-arch-linux">Personal - Installing and Configuring Arch Linux</h2>
<h4 id="from-february-2021-to-march-2021">From February 2021 to March 2021</h4>
<h4 id="description-1">Description</h4>
<p>Installed and customized Arch Linux from scratch to learn more about how the operating systems work and have full control over my computing experience.</p>
<p>Having used Ubuntu for some university work, I became fascinated seeing what was possible to do in a Linux computer and how efficient some desktops were. So, during a vacation period, I created a second partition in my computer and installed Arch Linux, customizing it to fit my needs. After some long hours reading documentation, erasing and rewriting partitions and even starting completely from scratch several times, victory was finally achieved.</p>
<p>The result is a desktop that works how I want it and allows me to be much more efficient, aside from being a much better environment to work on. Also, I now have complete knowledge of what is installed in my computer and how everything works and interacts with it, giving me a greater knowledge about the different components, and lighting up a passion for keeping on learning and discovering more about this field. I may even write a post about it someday! 👀</p>
<h4 id="technologies-used-1">Technologies used</h4>
<ul>
<li>Arch Linux - Operating system of a certain complexity but not too exaggerated.</li>
<li>Git - Management tool used for installing some extra packages not available in repositories.</li>
<li>Vim and Doom Emacs - Text editors used for setting up the system (and to configure themselves).</li>
<li>BSPWM - Window manager responsible for desktop configuration.</li>
<li>SXHKD - Program responsible for managing key binds that are used in the system.</li>
<li>Polybar - System bar with a set of useful widgets and information.</li>
<li>Rofi - App Launcher and System Control Widgets.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="personal---this-website">Personal - This website!</h2>
<h4 id="from-december-2021-to-today">From December 2021 to Today</h4>
<h4 id="description-2">Description</h4>
<p>Built my personal website and hosted on Github Pages, using a custom domain.</p>
<p>I always wanted a website, a place to share my thoughts with the world and one where I can build the experience users have when they enter. Finally, this Christmas, it happened (thanks Grandma).</p>
<p>To start, my grandma gifted me the domain. I had built some minor websites for university, but nothing like this. Since I never had built anything like this, I wanted to start by something small, in this case with a static website and a static website generator. I chose Hugo because it had some awesome themes and the setup was super quick. In the future I would love to build my own website template, but built from the ground up. Since I discovered the world of web development, Angular has always fascinated me (much more so than React). So stick around because in the future this website will probably be rebuilt with Angular and my very own CDN (it sounds impossible right now but a person can dream).</p>
<p>Even though it is not perfect, I have learned a great deal from assembling this, from linking domain names and redirects, SSL certificates, web hosting, and the art of publishing and keeping the local result the same as the remote one (an art that I learned by failing a lot of times, sadly). I also gained knowledge about the Jamstack and its benefits to the web (it is what I am using right now!), and finally, I gained a love for web development and a desire to learn a lot more than the small amount I know now. Hopefully in the future this will be one of my best projects!</p>
<h4 id="technologies-used-2">Technologies used</h4>
<ul>
<li>Hugo - Static Website Generator used.</li>
<li>Github Pages - Web host, great for static websites.</li>
<li>Doom Emacs - Text editor used for writing posts.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rhazdon/hugo-theme-hello-friend-ng">Hello-friend-ng</a> - Theme used to style the website.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="education">Education</h1>
<h2 id="july-2022--bachelors-degree">July 2022 – Bachelor&rsquo;s Degree</h2>
<h4 id="informatics-and-computer-engineering">Informatics and Computer Engineering</h4>
<h4 id="faculty-of-engineering-of-the-university-of-porto-feup">Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto (FEUP)</h4>
<h2 id="june-2019--high-school">June 2019 – High School</h2>
<h4 id="curso-científico-humanístico-de-ciências-e-tecnologias">Curso Científico-Humanístico de Ciências e Tecnologias</h4>
<h4 id="escola-secundária-de-barcelos">Escola Secundária de Barcelos</h4>
<h1 id="languages">Languages</h1>
<h3 id="portuguese">Portuguese:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Understanding: Native.</li>
<li>Speaking: Native.</li>
<li>Writing: Native.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="english">English</h3>
<ul>
<li>Understanding: C2 (Advanced).</li>
<li>Speaking: B2 (Independent).</li>
<li>Writing: C2 (Advanced).</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hi guys</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 17:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</guid>
            <description>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to try, right?
That&amp;rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&amp;rsquo;m fine).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&rsquo;t hurt to try, right?</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&rsquo;m fine).</p>
<p>You can find me in either Barcelos or Porto, depending on whether I am at university or chilling during my vacations.</p>
<h1 id="education">Education</h1>
<p>I am studying Informatics and Computer Engineering in <a href="https://fe.up.pt">FEUP</a> for a Bachelors degree, but I do intend on getting a Masters after it. It has been a crazy wild ride really, and I am loving it.</p>
<p>Before this, during high school, I went to Escola de Secundária de Barcelos, where I graduated with an 18.5 out of 20. Everyone&rsquo;s experience in high school is different but I think some of the best years of my life where spent in this school, maybe one day I&rsquo;ll even write about them.</p>
<h1 id="fun-stuff-i-like-doing">Fun Stuff I like doing</h1>
<p>The thing I most enjoy doing in this world is definitely to travel (bonus points if I go with my girlfriend). If it was possible, I would love to one day visit every country in the world at least once, kind of like <a href="https://onestep4ward.com/my-journey-to-every-country-in-the-world-country-list-and-faq/">this guy did</a>, even though that would take a lifetime to complete.</p>
<p>If I am forced to be at home, then my favorite thing in the world is definitely tinkering with my computer, especially the software department (I am studying software engineering after all). Maybe one day I will even show you my setup. When I want to go analog though, I usually try to read some books on how I can improve my life (I love stuff about habit-building and productivity in general), and recently I have discovered that I love learning new languages, and the less usual the better. Currently, I know Portuguese (duh) and English, and I am trying to learn Norwegian. Also I intend to one day expand to a language from out of Europe, as an extra challenge.</p>
<p>Finally, I am a gamer at heart. Ever since I first started playing on my PlayStation when I was like 10 and to this day, I have loved the experience that only games can give you. One of my favorite ways to spend time is playing TFT with my girlfriend, or exploring the Nordic myths and legends first-hand in God of War.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>As you can probably see I can find things that fascinate me in just about everything. If that is a blessing or a curse is up to you, but for me, it means that there will never be a dull moment in my life, and that I will always have something fun to talk about, be it with my lovely girlfriend, my family, my friends, and now with anyone that stumbles across this little piece of the internet. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
