<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</title>
        <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 17:04:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Hi guys</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 17:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</guid>
            <description>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to try, right?
That&amp;rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&amp;rsquo;m fine).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&rsquo;t hurt to try, right?</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&rsquo;m fine).</p>
<p>You can find me in either Barcelos or Porto, depending on whether I am at university or chilling during my vacations.</p>
<h1 id="education">Education</h1>
<p>I am studying Informatics and Computer Engineering in <a href="https://fe.up.pt">FEUP</a> for a Bachelors degree, but I do intend on getting a Masters after it. It has been a crazy wild ride really, and I am loving it.</p>
<p>Before this, during high school, I went to Escola de Secundária de Barcelos, where I graduated with an 18.5 out of 20. Everyone&rsquo;s experience in high school is different but I think some of the best years of my life where spent in this school, maybe one day I&rsquo;ll even write about them.</p>
<h1 id="fun-stuff-i-like-doing">Fun Stuff I like doing</h1>
<p>The thing I most enjoy doing in this world is definitely to travel (bonus points if I go with my girlfriend). If it was possible, I would love to one day visit every country in the world at least once, kind of like <a href="https://onestep4ward.com/my-journey-to-every-country-in-the-world-country-list-and-faq/">this guy did</a>, even though that would take a lifetime to complete.</p>
<p>If I am forced to be at home, then my favorite thing in the world is definitely tinkering with my computer, especially the software department (I am studying software engineering after all). Maybe one day I will even show you my setup. When I want to go analog though, I usually try to read some books on how I can improve my life (I love stuff about habit-building and productivity in general), and recently I have discovered that I love learning new languages, and the less usual the better. Currently, I know Portuguese (duh) and English, and I am trying to learn Norwegian. Also I intend to one day expand to a language from out of Europe, as an extra challenge.</p>
<p>Finally, I am a gamer at heart. Ever since I first started playing on my PlayStation when I was like 10 and to this day, I have loved the experience that only games can give you. One of my favorite ways to spend time is playing TFT with my girlfriend, or exploring the Nordic myths and legends first-hand in God of War.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>As you can probably see I can find things that fascinate me in just about everything. If that is a blessing or a curse is up to you, but for me, it means that there will never be a dull moment in my life, and that I will always have something fun to talk about, be it with my lovely girlfriend, my family, my friends, and now with anyone that stumbles across this little piece of the internet. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
