<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</title>
        <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 19:34:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Resume</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/resume/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 19:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/resume/</guid>
            <description>If you prefer a PDF version, you can find one here.
Experience Summary I am a third-year student currently getting a bachelor’s degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering. I love getting involved in new environments and meeting new people, because only then can I develop as a person and reach new heights.
During the summer of 2021, to challenge myself, I did a small internship at a company in my hometown, where I dealt with completely different circumstances compared to the ones faced in university, and had to learn new skills by myself, which in turn greatly improved my ability to learn on the fly and become even more passionate about this field.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you prefer a PDF version, you can find one <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1KwOkKca15Qu0sQ3muh21ADBqYabnHrEr/view?usp=sharing">here</a>.</p>
<h1 id="experience-summary">Experience Summary</h1>
<p>I am a third-year student currently getting a bachelor’s degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering. I love getting involved in new environments and meeting new people, because only then can I develop as a person and reach new heights.</p>
<p>During the summer of 2021, to challenge myself, I did a small internship at a company in my hometown, where I dealt with completely different circumstances compared to the ones faced in university, and had to learn new skills by myself, which in turn greatly improved my ability to learn on the fly and become even more passionate about this field.</p>
<p>And now, during Christmas, my grandmother told me to choose a gift, and so I chose this! It is a great way to learn about a field I am starting to love more and more, and it is a great way to train and have a sandbox where I can try new things.</p>
<h1 id="skills">Skills</h1>
<p><strong>Levels</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 - Curious about, eager to learn</li>
<li>2 - Begginer and Academic training only</li>
<li>3 - Small Projects and/or Internships</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="programming">Programming</h2>
<p>These are the languages I know best:</p>
<ul>
<li>HTML, CSS and JavaScript - 3</li>
<li>C# - 3</li>
<li>C/C++ - 2</li>
<li>Java - 2</li>
<li>PHP - 2</li>
<li>PostgreSQL and SQLite - 2</li>
<li>Haskell - 2</li>
<li>Python - 2</li>
<li>TypeScript - 1</li>
<li>Rust - 1</li>
<li>Go - 1</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="operating-systems">Operating Systems</h2>
<ul>
<li>Linux (Arch Linux, Ubuntu) - 3</li>
<li>Windows 10 - 3</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="frameworks">Frameworks</h2>
<ul>
<li>Bootstrap - 3</li>
<li>.NET - 3</li>
<li>Laravel - 2</li>
<li>Angular - 1</li>
<li>NestJs - 1</li>
<li>React - 1</li>
<li>TailwindCSS - 1</li>
<li>Flutter - 1</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="tools-i-use">Tools I use</h2>
<ul>
<li>Emacs (Doom Emacs) - 2</li>
<li>VSCode - 2</li>
<li>Vim (NeoVim) - 2</li>
<li>Git/Github/GitLab 2</li>
<li>Hugo - 2</li>
<li>Figma - 1</li>
<li>LaTeX - 1</li>
<li>Visual Studio - 3</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="projects">Projects</h1>
<h2 id="websystems---full-stack-web-developer">Websystems - Full Stack Web Developer</h2>
<h4 id="from-july-2021-to-september-2021">From July 2021 to September 2021</h4>
<h4 id="description">Description</h4>
<p>The project intended to expand their administration dashboard, which was used to monitor assets about their clients, as well as serving as a task manager for the whole Websystems team.</p>
<p>My goal was to add the ability to store information about the hardware and software of all the different clients, namely their workstations, servers, printers, among many others, integrate with the rest of the information and create a new section in the dashboard for display.</p>
<p>To do this I had to update the database to include the new tables, develop the front-end for presentation and easy retrieval of the information, and the back-end for processing all of the information sent, using an MVC architecture as a basis for the structure.</p>
<h4 id="technologies-used">Technologies used</h4>
<ul>
<li>C# - Page Controllers and Models created using an Object Relational Mapper.</li>
<li>ASP.NET Framework - Facilitating development of the application with built-in templates and tools.</li>
<li>Microsoft SQL Server - DBMS used to store the information.</li>
<li>HTML with Razor Templating Engine - Views and presentation of the information.</li>
<li>CSS and JavaScript - Visual styling and animations in the presented page.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="personal---installing-and-configuring-arch-linux">Personal - Installing and Configuring Arch Linux</h2>
<h4 id="from-february-2021-to-march-2021">From February 2021 to March 2021</h4>
<h4 id="description-1">Description</h4>
<p>Installed and customized Arch Linux from scratch to learn more about how the operating systems work and have full control over my computing experience.</p>
<p>Having used Ubuntu for some university work, I became fascinated seeing what was possible to do in a Linux computer and how efficient some desktops were. So, during a vacation period, I created a second partition in my computer and installed Arch Linux, customizing it to fit my needs. After some long hours reading documentation, erasing and rewriting partitions and even starting completely from scratch several times, victory was finally achieved.</p>
<p>The result is a desktop that works how I want it and allows me to be much more efficient, aside from being a much better environment to work on. Also, I now have complete knowledge of what is installed in my computer and how everything works and interacts with it, giving me a greater knowledge about the different components, and lighting up a passion for keeping on learning and discovering more about this field. I may even write a post about it someday! 👀</p>
<h4 id="technologies-used-1">Technologies used</h4>
<ul>
<li>Arch Linux - Operating system of a certain complexity but not too exaggerated.</li>
<li>Git - Management tool used for installing some extra packages not available in repositories.</li>
<li>Vim and Doom Emacs - Text editors used for setting up the system (and to configure themselves).</li>
<li>BSPWM - Window manager responsible for desktop configuration.</li>
<li>SXHKD - Program responsible for managing key binds that are used in the system.</li>
<li>Polybar - System bar with a set of useful widgets and information.</li>
<li>Rofi - App Launcher and System Control Widgets.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="personal---this-website">Personal - This website!</h2>
<h4 id="from-december-2021-to-today">From December 2021 to Today</h4>
<h4 id="description-2">Description</h4>
<p>Built my personal website and hosted on Github Pages, using a custom domain.</p>
<p>I always wanted a website, a place to share my thoughts with the world and one where I can build the experience users have when they enter. Finally, this Christmas, it happened (thanks Grandma).</p>
<p>To start, my grandma gifted me the domain. I had built some minor websites for university, but nothing like this. Since I never had built anything like this, I wanted to start by something small, in this case with a static website and a static website generator. I chose Hugo because it had some awesome themes and the setup was super quick. In the future I would love to build my own website template, but built from the ground up. Since I discovered the world of web development, Angular has always fascinated me (much more so than React). So stick around because in the future this website will probably be rebuilt with Angular and my very own CDN (it sounds impossible right now but a person can dream).</p>
<p>Even though it is not perfect, I have learned a great deal from assembling this, from linking domain names and redirects, SSL certificates, web hosting, and the art of publishing and keeping the local result the same as the remote one (an art that I learned by failing a lot of times, sadly). I also gained knowledge about the Jamstack and its benefits to the web (it is what I am using right now!), and finally, I gained a love for web development and a desire to learn a lot more than the small amount I know now. Hopefully in the future this will be one of my best projects!</p>
<h4 id="technologies-used-2">Technologies used</h4>
<ul>
<li>Hugo - Static Website Generator used.</li>
<li>Github Pages - Web host, great for static websites.</li>
<li>Doom Emacs - Text editor used for writing posts.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rhazdon/hugo-theme-hello-friend-ng">Hello-friend-ng</a> - Theme used to style the website.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="education">Education</h1>
<h2 id="july-2022--bachelors-degree">July 2022 – Bachelor&rsquo;s Degree</h2>
<h4 id="informatics-and-computer-engineering">Informatics and Computer Engineering</h4>
<h4 id="faculty-of-engineering-of-the-university-of-porto-feup">Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto (FEUP)</h4>
<h2 id="june-2019--high-school">June 2019 – High School</h2>
<h4 id="curso-científico-humanístico-de-ciências-e-tecnologias">Curso Científico-Humanístico de Ciências e Tecnologias</h4>
<h4 id="escola-secundária-de-barcelos">Escola Secundária de Barcelos</h4>
<h1 id="languages">Languages</h1>
<h3 id="portuguese">Portuguese:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Understanding: Native.</li>
<li>Speaking: Native.</li>
<li>Writing: Native.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="english">English</h3>
<ul>
<li>Understanding: C2 (Advanced).</li>
<li>Speaking: B2 (Independent).</li>
<li>Writing: C2 (Advanced).</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hi guys</title>
            <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 17:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</guid>
            <description>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to try, right?
That&amp;rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&amp;rsquo;m fine).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&rsquo;t hurt to try, right?</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&rsquo;m fine).</p>
<p>You can find me in either Barcelos or Porto, depending on whether I am at university or chilling during my vacations.</p>
<h1 id="education">Education</h1>
<p>I am studying Informatics and Computer Engineering in <a href="https://fe.up.pt">FEUP</a> for a Bachelors degree, but I do intend on getting a Masters after it. It has been a crazy wild ride really, and I am loving it.</p>
<p>Before this, during high school, I went to Escola de Secundária de Barcelos, where I graduated with an 18.5 out of 20. Everyone&rsquo;s experience in high school is different but I think some of the best years of my life where spent in this school, maybe one day I&rsquo;ll even write about them.</p>
<h1 id="fun-stuff-i-like-doing">Fun Stuff I like doing</h1>
<p>The thing I most enjoy doing in this world is definitely to travel (bonus points if I go with my girlfriend). If it was possible, I would love to one day visit every country in the world at least once, kind of like <a href="https://onestep4ward.com/my-journey-to-every-country-in-the-world-country-list-and-faq/">this guy did</a>, even though that would take a lifetime to complete.</p>
<p>If I am forced to be at home, then my favorite thing in the world is definitely tinkering with my computer, especially the software department (I am studying software engineering after all). Maybe one day I will even show you my setup. When I want to go analog though, I usually try to read some books on how I can improve my life (I love stuff about habit-building and productivity in general), and recently I have discovered that I love learning new languages, and the less usual the better. Currently, I know Portuguese (duh) and English, and I am trying to learn Norwegian. Also I intend to one day expand to a language from out of Europe, as an extra challenge.</p>
<p>Finally, I am a gamer at heart. Ever since I first started playing on my PlayStation when I was like 10 and to this day, I have loved the experience that only games can give you. One of my favorite ways to spend time is playing TFT with my girlfriend, or exploring the Nordic myths and legends first-hand in God of War.</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>As you can probably see I can find things that fascinate me in just about everything. If that is a blessing or a curse is up to you, but for me, it means that there will never be a dull moment in my life, and that I will always have something fun to talk about, be it with my lovely girlfriend, my family, my friends, and now with anyone that stumbles across this little piece of the internet. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
