<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</title>
    <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 18:57:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Navy Seal Training 2</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 18:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-2/</guid>
      <description>Week 2 was yet another one of my terrific failures. It seems that the start of this challenge is going to be the worst part of them all. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right that after all the continuous hard work put in during the semester, I still have to complete exams on top of it (which sadly, most of them didn&amp;rsquo;t go as I expected). This little journey is also becoming a bit of a weekly insight into my life which is not the original plan, but one I don&amp;rsquo;t mind at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 1</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 11:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-1/</guid>
      <description>I have to be honest, during week one I was terrible. Not because I found the training hard and was constantly sore from doing it, but because I didn&amp;rsquo;t even actually train in most of the days. It felt terrible doing this to myself, even more so when I was just starting and was supposed to at least try in the first week, it didn&amp;rsquo;t go at all according to plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 0</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-0/</guid>
      <description>Navy SEALs are tough people, there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt about it.
From David Goggins to Jocko Willink and all others, they can inspire everyone to become a better version of themselves. And that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what they did to me. I come from Portugal, but for a period of my life around the time I was 11 and dreamy, I was convinced I would join the SEALs, breeze through training and be a part of the elite, jumping from airplanes in enemy territory and going on crazy missions around the world, just like in the movies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
