<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</title>
    <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hey guys, I&#39;m Tiago</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 07:25:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 8</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 07:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-8/</guid>
      <description>As I look back into this week, I can see that it was destined for failure from the get-go.
Although this time I had brought everything and felt prepared for the rest of the day, it quickly became quite overwhelming.
Busy scheduling Monday was still an easy day, just like every other day. I woke up early, did my full workout quite relaxed knowing I had an extra 30 minutes, and headed to class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 7</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 19:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-7/</guid>
      <description>With the semester in full swing now, I can start planting the seed for a definitive routine for the rest of the year.
The plans that I had started back in Week 0 could be implemented to their fullest, and I could finally start having the real-life I wanted in university, being a T-shaped person (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of that before, here is a good article explaining it).
As usual, I came to Porto on Sunday after packing in a rush, and when I got here I didn&amp;rsquo;t even think about what I brought, I just offloaded everything and went to rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 6</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 18:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-6/</guid>
      <description>As the start of the new semester was rapidly approaching, I decided to make sure that I would follow up and prioritize my training above almost all else (education is the major exception).
This happenned because I noticed that, during some interviews for potential internships, no one really asked me about my grades or how good my results were. People only cared about what I produced.
So, if they don&amp;rsquo;t really care about my grades, and I am learning either way, then why should I spend nearly every single minute worried about each and every little detail that won&amp;rsquo;t make a big difference in the end?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 5</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 16:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-5/</guid>
      <description>This was most definitely a week of adaptation. After the first week of vacations had passed, I went back to my hometown to be with my parents for a while. This led to some great times of course, but also some workout difficulties.
Choosing a new spot In previous times, I would be fine working out in Barcelos, as I had a gym close to home during summer break. The problem is that I only could go to that gym for summer break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 4</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 13:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-4/</guid>
      <description>After such an intensive week like week 3, week 4 started out in a really slow fashion.
It was impressive how little physical stamina I had up to this point, and Friday and the futsal game really showed it. The coming days were challenging as hell, with Saturday and Sunday me being barely able to move my muscles and lift my legs, which led to me not leaving the house at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Years Since the Best Trip of My Life</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/trip-to-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 21:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/trip-to-london/</guid>
      <description>This is the story of the best gift I ever received, and one of the best I probably will ever receive.
The Origin Story It all started when I turned 18. It is always a special occasion, and with me being born late in December, it was even more exciting after seeing all of my friends having their great parties and moments.
That year was also the year I started dating Daniela, so it was even better as it was my first birthday I would spend with a &amp;ldquo;special someone&amp;rdquo;, something every teen would love to have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 3</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 11:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-3/</guid>
      <description>For the first time since the start of this challenge, I started this week off with a blast. When Monday came, and the big exam was done, I immediately decided it was time for a change. Now that only a single exam remains, and one that I am hoping to be quite the easy challenge, I finally had the time to kill it in my workouts and give my all without the fear of falling behind in university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 2</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 18:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-2/</guid>
      <description>Week 2 was yet another one of my terrific failures. It seems that the start of this challenge is going to be the worst part of them all. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right that after all the continuous hard work put in during the semester, I still have to complete exams on top of it (which sadly, most of them didn&amp;rsquo;t go as I expected). This little journey is also becoming a bit of a weekly insight into my life which is not the original plan, but one I don&amp;rsquo;t mind at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 1</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 11:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-1/</guid>
      <description>I have to be honest, during week one I was terrible. Not because I found the training hard and was constantly sore from doing it, but because I didn&amp;rsquo;t even actually train in most of the days. It felt terrible doing this to myself, even more so when I was just starting and was supposed to at least try in the first week, it didn&amp;rsquo;t go at all according to plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Trained to Look Like a Navy Seal - Week 0</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/navy-seal-training-0/</guid>
      <description>Navy SEALs are tough people, there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt about it.
From David Goggins to Jocko Willink and all others, they can inspire everyone to become a better version of themselves. And that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what they did to me. I come from Portugal, but for a period of my life around the time I was 11 and dreamy, I was convinced I would join the SEALs, breeze through training and be a part of the elite, jumping from airplanes in enemy territory and going on crazy missions around the world, just like in the movies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 19:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/resume/</guid>
      <description>If you prefer a PDF version, you can find one here.
Experience Summary I am a third-year student currently getting a bachelor’s degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering. I love getting involved in new environments and meeting new people, because only then can I develop as a person and reach new heights.
During the summer of 2021, to challenge myself, I did a small internship at a company in my hometown, where I dealt with completely different circumstances compared to the ones faced in university, and had to learn new skills by myself, which in turn greatly improved my ability to learn on the fly and become even more passionate about this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 19:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>If you prefer a PDF version, you can find one here.
Experience Summary I am a third-year student currently getting a bachelor’s degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering. I love getting involved in new environments and meeting new people, because only then can I develop as a person and reach new heights.
During the summer of 2021, to challenge myself, I did a small internship at a company in my hometown, where I dealt with completely different circumstances compared to the ones faced in university, and had to learn new skills by myself, which in turn greatly improved my ability to learn on the fly and become even more passionate about this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi guys</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 17:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to try, right?
That&amp;rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&amp;rsquo;m fine).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi guys</title>
      <link>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 17:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiagopbrodrigues.com/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Tiago Rodrigues. I come from a little place in Portugal called Milhazes, and my goal in life is to try and learn as much as possible from everything. Some say that might be a bit too ambitious but hey, doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to try, right?
That&amp;rsquo;s probably why I started this little page as well, to try and create a record of what I am doing, where I am and share a bit of my life with anyone that might be interested (hey mom, yes I&amp;rsquo;m fine).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
